[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
what is cracking my brows welcome to the
Gian Carlo podcast this is Jacob Brian's
just letting you know that this episode
was recorded kind of about a month ago
before it's being posted I had plans for
a lot of these upcoming episodes to edit
them while I was traveling and in hotel
rooms and these sort of things so I had
just recorded a ton right before I was
about to leave and then the coronavirus
hit so I'm just back logged in I haven't
um totally caught up so I am I am just
trying to make sure I post that they
were not very recent so this was a
little over a month old but it's a brand
new to your year so enjoy this episode
of Ryan Reed before we get going I'm
gonna give a recommendation the
recommendation today is not in the form
of a book or a TED talk because Ryan and
I give a ton of book recommendations
later on in this podcast so stay tuned
for that but um also let's just
recommend the good place on Netflix
that's just a TV show on Netflix it's
about philosophy moral philosophy it's
quite wonderful and stretch your mind a
little bit
check it out on Netflix the good place
let's get going me Ryan Reid half-life
ent let's go eat checking microphone
chick alright Ryan Reid you beautiful
man damn you
welcome to the jianci I love podcasts
how are you today my friend specifically
specifically today man I was your
morning and everything today's a little
stressed yeah yeah we had a great
weekend we on Friday we performed at an
all-ages show in Gresham which is cool
it was alright we're trying to expand
more and so the all-ages thing just
because you know we need to expand our
demographic and you know to be honest
that's a lot of the younger folk they
determine what's next and what's what's
cool yeah I can't forget about that so
we've been trying to endeavor into all
ages but
the hard part too is that if the
all-ages kids are just there to like
turn up and listen to music that they
know like hake we just have the box by
roddy rich on repeat the whole night
they did okay with that okay wrong is a
bot but yeah so then you're like yeah
but check out what we're doing and
they're like yeah but like you bring the
box back you don't I mean so they want
to show off the dance move they practice
in private bro right exactly exactly so
been diving into that which we can get
into a little more after I answer the
first question and then Saturday we had
a comedy show Max had his first like
stand-up comedy show that wasn't
revolved around that wasn't part of like
a halflife event and that went amazing
he killed that super proud of him and
and the way that he's been pursuing that
ambition of his and so we had that on
Saturday that went really dope Sunday we
filmed a new music video for Rula
Delgado for the song called the one
which is available on all streaming
platforms the one by Roulet Delgado it's
really good as our MB and he's got some
R&B chops and that song is incredible
it dropped on Valentine's Day because
the one you know of course so we filmed
that and then so then it was just like
this this busy busy busy weekend and
then I woke up today and like a bunch of
messages and stuff hit me and it was
like oh my god I have so much unfinished
business I have so much just like the
work still comes right so I kind of woke
up from this like amazing haze cuz when
you start to do like multiple shows in a
row and stuff mentally you're like oh
this is the life and then you have to
like wake back up to reality right and
remember all the business side of things
that have not been done your Monday
still comes bro money still comes man
and so there's just so much stuff to do
and so so that's where I woke up I woke
up very busy minded today okay but maybe
that'll help with the conversation
yeah I'm not to be too erratic we got
hey bro I'll rub off on you if you art
we'll both be alright I mean if people
are listening this podcast they know
things go erratically if one's right
well I mean they follow in my brain here
so exactly so we can just combine our
crazy mazes and we'll just we'll just be
two mice in the maze yeah I know cheese
together
you know speaking of - I have an
interesting fact about - to teach you to
tell you about - gosh when they called -
lemierre's - lemierre's it's a everybody
has them they're like I'm gonna totally
butcher this fact now essentially here's
the fact I was listening to Brett
Weinstein and Eric Weinstein they're
brothers and they study like just
everything biology and economics and
mathematics and just everything there
are some professors essentially with
mice they've learned that a lot of the
mice that we've been testing on for like
America just like cosmetics food
supplements like everything from pretty
much this one factory of my so this one
place in the United States and which is
like cool that's great you know we have
things that they have it probably down
there they probably the best the best
but right what happens is after like
eight months or something they kill them
- or after eight months like essentially
they've made these like these are like a
superhuman sort of mice or a super mice
that don't live because we only test
products on mice that are under eight
months old or something okay and so
essentially these mice over the years
because they're just built as like
cosmetic testing mice or whatever it is
they have like grown into like a
different type of mice that died after
eight months are they whatever so they
have their telomeres telomeres I'm
saying them incorrectly which is what we
test like this is like our similarities
between them and mice in humans so what
I'm rounding out is we have been testing
on mice thinking that they're
representing humans in the long term the
longevity of a human lifetime but we're
actually like testing it on mice that
would be representing like ages 1 to 30
right yeah so would that wouldn't you
also not want to condition these super
mice because then wouldn't that almost
make everything a little bit bias yes
like you're not you know because they're
gonna grow genetically they're gonna
start maybe being like less affected by
certain thing yes so wouldn't we be
getting botched yes that's what's
happened so this is like the chickens
this is like big a chicken yeah like
they don't even hardly lay most of time
they don't even have to use hormones
anymore because selective breeding has
made it to where they live
those weeks - that's so fast though if
you think about it like in like terms of
like just evolution oh they did that so
quickly to the baby and in me like if
your baby was like 800 pounds like that
oh yeah like like they're so they die at
six weeks they're butchered at six weeks
so they after they've been selective
breeding till they're so that they're
full-grown by like six weeks and like
they can't even hardly walk
you know legs came to support them their
legs are broken they're having heart
attacks like you'll have a lot of them
died due to heart attacks but big
chicken man they'll they'll just you
know they pay you based on they pay
these farms based on how big they are
and how many big ones not how well did
you treat these chickens up until the
process of circle of life here you know
have you seen okay you should watch some
members supersize me yeah yeah okay so
Super Size Me 2 came out nobody knew
about it because he ended up being on
the wrong side of the meat to movement
and yeah like right before Super Size Me
2 was this was supposed to drop so but
regardless still the name in the
clintons on that right exactly
regardless of how you feel about him
though it was very intriguing because
basically what he doesn't supersize me
too is he's like I'm gonna start a
fast-food restaurant and then it shows
the whole process from getting the
chicks all the way to like the marketing
schemes and yeah ok what was it like was
it liked it was it did he showed us how
gross and like you know like hey man it
all is all of the the secrets and like
he calls at one point this is one little
tidbit about it he's like so how much
free-range do they need to be for me to
be able to put on my package free-range
and it's like it's like well as long as
they have like access to outdoors if
they want so he literally puts like this
like maybe three square feet like
addition to the end oh yeah the end of
the fungus hits a [__] wall with a
hammer and open so there's like this
three square foot area where if they
want to the communal sunlight free range
he exposes everything dude that's what
we have if you if you go to the
supermarket you go to the store you go
anywhere a gas station and you like read
these things what we read is we're like
oh low in calories or or low fat or low
whatever like it
do these things and we think oh those
are good indicators of I should buy that
that's good for me that's not gonna be I
know that's better than McDonald's but
like a lot of the times a lot of these
indicators that they put are just
[__] like the free-range
psychological yeah yeah they're playing
with this man like you know what my
favorite one is what's that because
there's a lot that are like you know
there's a lot that you're like okay sure
but one of my favorites is farm-raised
arm race okay yeah they'll literally put
that as a tag like farm-raised and
you're like where else doesn't matter
how terrible the conditions are it's
still called a farm for that too will be
the quotes farm right like more like hey
can you pick me up some like good like
not that none of that shitty chicken
just give me some like good okay so farm
raised yes sweet home alabama'
right you know can we go me there's an
episode of the show Portlandia which is
this drastically have you seen that one
essentially they go and they get like
they're going to get breakfast and
they're like so the the eggs are the
chickens that lay the eggs
cruelty free or whatever and the the
waitress is like you know let me double
check and she goes back and get some
info about the chickens and comes back
and like I don't know like were they are
they treated well before they arrived
like it and then it's essentially the
whole episode of Portlandia as them like
going to this farm and they're like farm
for like don't they like live on the
farm or something to experience it
because it feels like a combine or
something like like oh yeah like the
scene ends they go back to the
restaurant or something I think and
they're like oh yeah I think we'll go
with this like you like we made our
decision it's like that's the thing is
you you know we have so many there's so
many trickle downs in the way that like
our economics work the way that our
world works it's so hard to know like
like we what you want is you want to be
able to read the package and trust that
like your government trusts these
companies are like this is good for you
or this is bad for you or like eat this
much of this thing don't eat whole
package or whatever but like instead we
have trick words you know right trick
words and so you would actually really
enjoy and any
who is listening to this podcast and
also is you know fascinate wait I should
say if you don't want to live
ignorant ly blissful about food don't
watch it but if you are curious about
that information
definitely watch supersize me - because
they even talk about like the tag lines
and everything you know so he's like and
I won't spoil the ending but you know
they talk about the fact that because
there's there's actually a fun twist but
they actually talk about like oh like if
we put the word fresh next to went
lettuce really big with like a juicy
tomato it's gonna seem like we've made
these large advances in making our fast
food more health right right and it's
all a bunch of shenanigans and then you
know he basically based on the
conditions of his chickens he calls up
I forget which company deals with you
know like certified organic and all that
good stuff right in the US FDA FDA the
FDA and I don't said the USA DEA and oh
that's all right but he calls them up
and he's like okay so what all
categories am i okay to say on my
package like so they go through and
they're like alright so okay you could
say no hormones that's fine you could
say antibiotic free you can't do
certified organic because there was
trace amounts of chicken in your feed so
you have cannibal chicken but the
free-range one got me because he
literally makes this like little fence
and he's like free-range farm raised
dude that's how it is it's you know it's
it's a bunch of people we have laws in
place is the thing like we have laws in
place a lot of them should be like Rhian
spected of course but they're like
people are like I'm going it I'm not
breaking the law my hands are in the air
it's like dude you know what you're
doing though you know what's going on
right yeah they don't care then the
other thing she'll be talking to
sideways or straight in oh yeah oh it
sounds yeah it goes straight up where
you know who that's folder have like a
Fuller's Murrah
so the other thing that was that was
interesting was oh shoot I got so caught
up in the tonality of my voice it makes
a dramatic difference it was very like
high frequency you know it's very laughs
like I should be more on top of that so
hey listener if you can if you just
heard the first few minutes of Ryan's
voice not as thin and ladylike as he
sounds right this is the real him this I
had him talking at different mic types
you talking to like different areas of
the mo
I'm Ryan Reed who are on the junkie
little podcast shoot was gonna say um
anyway supersize me zoom yeah yeah dude
I also in that same area I recommend
Shaylee and I just watched couple days
ago it's called that sugar film and it
is along the same lines essentially this
dude he eats super healthy he's in he's
a from Australia he eats really healthy
he cut out sugar long years ago but he
has a baby on the way and so he's like I
want to know like what's like I gotta
like know what what should I feed my
baby like he was all stressed about it
whatever so he's decided to go on like a
typical like what's a typical person's
diet like not worrying about sugar like
he doesn't care about sugar he's not
he's not watching out for it and it
turns out to be like it was like 40
grams of sugar or something that people
edia every day and so he followed his
like two months progress yeah there's a
surprise I'm more it might have been
more I could be totally awful than
sugars and everything well so that's the
thing is he did 60 days of so this is
someone for who like eats super healthy
does not intake sugar and then he went
to just eating crate like every single
day that much sugar did it for 60 days
any follow his progress I came to total
weight he was doing blood tests like all
these things kind like supersize me and
essentially what he what he showed is
like the trickery to of he didn't eat
like soda and candy and ice cream like
he had none of that like that was an
option he only ate like healthy things
so like he would buy like slimfast you
know like a low calorie or low fat like
he only ate the healthy stuff that they
sell us and he also he went from
Australia hated it there for the first
half came to America and then he did it
like for the next 30 days he did it
there he said he had more difficulty
eating healthy and keeping under his
allotted grams of sugar every day
in America that it was even over there
that doesn't surprise me oh yeah and so
it did it essentially what I got which
anything I got out of it was just more
reiteration of just like the [__] of
the The Lying of like this is healthy
for you and it's sad to me that we have
people with with cancer that seems so
mysterious and we have people with all
these things and all these illnesses
that are just being compounded by people
people in companies lying to them you
know right if it's healthy like you know
what that [__] means healthy like
don't hurt you're hurting this person
you know right yeah we don't care dude
it's something care is money yeah right
that's the way the world goes out for is
all the sugar alternatives right Oh
sucralose man right brother
shame all that they showed a good
example of like what that stuff does
inside your body what do we don't
process it and it's like right Blaine
okay so I feel like we're low-key like
segue into it did it work did it did so
you know because that's something that's
made a big change for me too with with
my health and we could get into that
right now if you want I would love to
get into Ryan tell me about your health
you had some changes in your house
lately yes
so because you know that reminds me of
the whole carb thing to people forget
that carbs or sugars and like they have
to be treated the same so last January
whoo all right so for those that are
listening it's probably March now and if
you don't know I had a huge change in my
health in January of 2020 and this is
the first time publicly talking about it
I didn't want to make a big deal about
it especially when I was in the hospital
I'm not the guy that's like you know I'm
no offense to the people that do I just
I don't like to put everything on social
media like if I didn't have a music and
entertainment company or a had do post
on social media Tom I wouldn't like just
me personally I just don't like to spend
a lot of time like posting and and doing
the social media game but unfortunately
I have to for my company right for
half-life entertainment so I didn't say
anything on social media I didn't want
to I didn't want a bunch of people to
know in fact my parents didn't even know
until I had it already handled but
January of 2020
I so I basically I started to get really
weak and really sick I started to feel
dehydrated constantly at all times and I
started drinking water because I was
always thirsty and I tried to
overcompensate for that but I was
drinking all this water but I was also
peeing like 30 times a day like nothing
was retaining I'm just I'm taking in
unlimited liquids and I'm peeing them
right back out this is going on for how
long was it till you die Quinta it was
like two weeks but it wasn't just that
it was the fact that I lost like I'm for
those that know me I don't have a lot of
body fat right I've always had trouble
gaining weight and even gaining muscle
and I never knew why I lost 12 pounds
within two weeks and at the time I was
only like you know a buck forty ish so
like I dipped down I started to monitor
my weight every morning because I was
like this isn't right like I stopped I
stopped drinking ice because I was doing
a cleanse anyway like who knew you knew
me you know but like I usually do that
like every few months Chris and I will
take like a couple weeks here or like a
month here like we'll just do little
like it alcohol cleanses anyway yeah we
do same thing right and so it was like
you get over that first five days when
you start to of not drinking and you get
past like the the crappy part of you
know getting rid of alcohol and then you
start to feel better then also in your
Energy's back getting up earlier in the
morning you're more hungry all this
stuff I was less hungry less energy
losing weight I start monitoring every
day and every day I'm waking up lighter
and I'm like this is nuts
I had you know I'm trying to work and my
muscles are weak I don't have energy and
like once I started dipping into like
the 120s I'm like something is very
wrong I haven't been this light since I
was cutting weight on purpose and for
wrestling in high school and that's what
it felt like
yeah that's small right like it felt
like I was cutting weight and I looked
you know small I would shriveling up
like a raisin and I was being I was
being stubborn
and I was like I don't know like I was
monitored a couple more days and then
Chris that was like not like we're going
in you know he's gonna keep saying
couple more days exactly cuz I you know
just being at the stubborn dude that I
am so she was like dr. unibrow right
exactly you know I mean you're like nah
stomach bug we'll get over it right so
but then I started I started googling
the I feel I got my symptoms went up and
I was like I think I know what this is
and so I went into a like a walk-in like
a Urgent Care because I didn't have
insurance at the time and I walk into an
urgent care and I'm like I need to be
tested for diabetes and they're like we
don't do that here and I'm like that's
weird
okay can you point to where they did I
helped and so they're like yeah so uh oh
it's just you has this this walk-in
clinic that you could go to and I'm like
oh cool so we go to that and I'm like
hey I need to be tested for diabetes
they take my blood sugar and my urine
and they're like you need to go to the
emergency room like my blood sugar
wouldn't even read on their device it
just said hi it was just all red and it
said hi she says so yes so I go into the
hospital I get admitted and they're like
yeah we know what to do and obviously I
went through like three IV bags and like
three saline solutions or whatever and
they're like I we're gonna need to
monitor you wanting to get you on
insulin we're gonna take a bunch of
blood tests but you are probably a
diabetic and I'm like okay so we so I
ended up staying there for four days but
they knew like day one right now it's
gonna be diabetic they wanted to prove
it with the blood test and why not that
would take a couple days but they pretty
much knew I knew it all just like it's
pretty cut and dry when like your
symptoms look like that and so sure
enough I am a type 1 diabetic not even
type - that's like based around diet and
stuff my pancreas officially does not
work anymore which actually made a lot
of things make sense over the last like
three to four years of why I was slowly
losing muscle mass and like not being
able to gain weight gain muscle
I felt sluggish for years so it's
something you've had like or it's been
coming on so basically what what it is
is that my pancreas slowly stopped
producing insulin but at a slow rate and
then what I learned is that I ended up
going into what's called ketoacidosis so
for if you don't know how insulin works
your pancreas creates insulin and what
insulins main job is is to take the
sugar out of your blood and it's the
gatekeeper to getting it into your cells
so with no insulin exactly yeah
who was the the blind man that rode you
across the river Styx
you'd have to in Creek mythology you'd
have to toss them a couple coins to get
you to hell and that's why or to the
underworld that's why they put two coins
over your eyes so you can give them to
the boat man so you can take it in the
world so basically that's insulin and
without that your your blood becomes so
just kind of clogged up with sugar and
then your cells think that you're
starving like your cells are like we're
not getting any sugar here we're legit
starving so they start to slowly eat
your fat and if you're somebody like me
who doesn't have fat it starts to slowly
eat your muscles after you don't have
any muscle left it starts to eat your
organs and so like ketoacidosis is
basically where your cells are like I
we've had it we're going full in and
then they basically start to have like a
buffet on your body and so that so it
was it was a process that now makes so
much sense that my insulin rate was
declining over the years and then
finally it was just done and that's why
I went into ketoacidosis and he was like
it's a good thing that my girlfriend
wasn't gonna let me keep me and stubborn
because he was like it was only a matter
of days before you went into
a dive like a coma I would have went
into like a ketoacidosis coma
great no not not great and so honest
kidding we have girls to save our life I
know right
we're so [__] helpless sometimes
they're like yo males are the alpha
species they're the alpha sex nope yeah
we would all kill these start kill each
other kill ourselves
barbaric we can't take care of ourselves
no we can't we really can't like she is
seriously she is she's the greatest
thing in my life
she's my rock I would die without her
she'll always be my best friend no
matter what but so so thanks to her I
didn't go into a coma but we started
getting on insulin immediately in the
hospital you know we we went through the
you know a bunch of IV and I started to
feel better immediately yeah and
basically the reason that they had to
keep me forage days is because they
can't they have to figure out what
insulin rate like levels like how many
units per day like works best with your
body because everybody needs different
levels and they can't just like hump you
with all of them right away so if they
start with X amount and if that doesn't
work then they need to pump it up and
monitor firday bump it up and monitor
you for a day and tell your addict come
fluent especially since you were pretty
skinny going in there too so right
you're just by changing as you're as
you're getting healthier right of course
in a couple days exactly and so we ended
up dialing it in I take a long-acting
24-hour insulin every night and then I
have to take short-term insulin before
each big meal depending on how many
carbs have and so that's what kind of
brought it up that note that I made
earlier about the carbs and the sugars
is that they're interchangeable with
diabetes like your body treats carbs and
sugars the same and so like I'm actually
counting my carbs to determine how many
units of insulin I need to take before
that meal to insure that I can get
whatever sugar that I'm about to intake
from my blood to my cells and make sure
that my body's feeding and
so when you take your when you take your
nightly one this is like a shot it's a
yeah it's so I have the Pens so
basically it's like a twist like I it
has X amount of units in it when I twist
how many units I need and then I have
like one use needles Oh perfect I just
screw on a one use needle put it into my
belly yeah how is that bad how have you
been adjusting to that part's fine I
have to take them everywhere
I got a you know taken before meals I
got to make sure that I don't forget at
night like it's a pain like you know
living with diabetes is going to change
your entire life right it has but that
part's not too bad the annoying part is
the blood sugar like pull it out my
thing
putting putting a reader chip in my
blood sugar monitor poking my finger
like you know that part's annoying but I
did get approved for one of those
constant glucose monitors little sip of
my hip and then I'll read off on my
phone
so wait does it does it stab you on your
hip too or yeah like you you put like a
needle a new needle in every two weeks
okay and then it's on there with like
sports tape basically like heavy-duty
medical tape and then you take your
transmitter and hook it up to that so
you'll keep the same transmitter where I
have a different needle every two weeks
for sanitary reasons that'd be great to
have yes I was reading my blood sugar
off my phone especially when I'm out you
know like doing shows and things like
that I don't want to like you know and
then I'll just make sure to have my
insulin with me so I could still take
insulin yeah and then also I feel like
just making fat beats with like a poked
finger
we're just suck you know what I mean you
know what the technology of these nano
needles is it a nano needle that it does
how's it feel as their it like you feel
like a little just hook and as long as
you like I do the sides and not the
actual like mmm flat top
yeah it doesn't bother with things I'm
doing let's do the sides and you just
keep rotating fingers there yeah but now
I won't have to do that near as much so
so that's that I now I'm up to a hundred
and fifty pounds great idea so I've
gained like you know 25 pounds from when
I was at my lowest when I went into the
hospital whoo and I feel incredible this
is the healthiest I've felt in years you
know I thought my lack of energy was
just like I guess this is
being an adult is just like being tired
all that I'm over that sentence
promising I'm saying it near me like man
like until your until you're [__] 80
years old you're like this is what I
guess I'm getting old now man right just
accepting the fact that you're feeling
crappy when you're 24 that ain't right
man right there's there's going to be
something wrong right and so for me it
took all of that to realize it but now
that I am on regular insulin and my body
is working like a normal human being I
feel great my energy has skyrocketed
like just just like so many little my
muscles feel dense again you know not
that I'm the strongest dude but like
they actually feel my muscles feel like
muscles you know what I mean it's crazy
so it's just it's really changed my
entire life for the better even though
yeah it can definitely be a pain in the
ass yeah I mean so it's a whole new like
just your day-to-day obviously is
different what's the house like the
mental shift been like obviously it's
like a scary moment like it's like oh
[__] like this is my health like no a
lot of times these sort of things he
kind of like wake us up to like just
like yeah I do want to take care of my
body
those sorts right so I don't know have
you had any like mental shifts at all
through it yeah so for one just being
excited to feel good and not always
wandering in the back of my head if
there's something late there was
definitely a weight off of my shoulders
because like I said I knew that there
was something funky for years right
right and so that's a good way to off of
my shoulders so there's that and then
with this new energy I just feel more
ambitious than I was before I feel like
my work ethic has increased once again
and I always tried to pride myself on
having a consistent strong work ethic so
to see that like on it's just been
really inspiring you know I mean and
like yeah like it's a big deal and a
huge change in my life but I was so
positive the entire time like I'm it
takes a lot to get me down like we all
have our rough days and everything but
like I really have put a lot of effort
into trying to be as positive as I can
and like recognizing that the way I want
to feel is on me like I have the power
to you know affect my
motions I am NOT a creature of
circumstance but rather a creator of
circumstance and I you know I've worked
really hard to take my own mentality
into my own mind I'm not saying that
that just dis credits you know like
mental illness and things like that I'm
not saying that at all I'm just saying
when I go I have a choice
where I don't need to be subject to the
energies around me and so that has just
increased tenfold and I was super
positive through the entire thing I
learned everything I needed to learn
ASAP my my endocrinologist and my
diabetes specialist were like damn I
like you you got it out you're good to
go you're accepting the fate yeah
exactly
well because here's the deal here's the
deal um you know I don't want to keep
hogging the mic the whole time but no
key pocket image you have plenty of room
thank you but whether like I have
diabetes
I'm a [__] diabetic whether I want to
be in a crappy mood about it or whether
I want to take it by the balls and
figure out how to live the best life
that I can or anywhere in the middle of
that scale it doesn't change the fact
that I have this disease yep so why on
earth would I let myself be beat up over
it day in and day out when I can just
make the changes I need to feel great
and then just attack life even harder
you're able to run you're able to see
things as and this is something that not
a lot of people haven't or they don't
have until they realize they don't have
it sometimes that's enough to like kind
of wake it up the in life there's things
that happen and we think that that's
exactly my reaction to that thing that
happens is exactly what happens all
right when my what life actually is is
there's a thing that happened and then
there's your reaction to it right two
entirely separate things and you've
always liked it obviously this is a
great example of who you are as a person
like you were positive through this dude
tell me about where you got this
positive mentality from like what you
your belief in yourself you're like wow
this is life like I'm going next like
you have this like just undefeatable
attitude I mean undefeatable I can think
that's best word I can think of
like there's nothing I like that where
did this come from tell me about about
the birth of this side of you uh just
losing yes like I feel I feel like I've
always been ambitious I've always felt
like I had a leadership attitude and
mentality and I always knew that I
wanted to do something impactful with my
life right like that much I feel like
I've always known I always felt like
there was something in me that I just
needed to figure out how to harness and
and figure out how to use it but I also
didn't know where it was supposed to
come from but I've been competitive my
entire life I used to race motocross
when I was in elementary school
punctured my lung doing that with the
dorm Becker's that's how we did that
benefit for her you know between
wrestling you know and and back in high
school like your sport is the most
nothing else matters in the world
besides that sport right and so like my
upsets with like State and things like
that like there was a lot of like
notions you know that I was given that
like hey you're you have greatness in
you but you need to figure out how to
properly harness it use it and and and
and where to put it and so like I was
always searching for where that
greatness was supposed to be but then
always coming up short and always
somehow getting [__] on yeah and so then
with the whole music thing like I fell
in love with music you know I mean
granted I used to I used to take guitar
lessons in elementary school and you
know I thought I was like max explained
you know I thought I was gonna be in a
rock band - it wasn't a Christian one
like I've been in a rock made myself I
know how it goes
I was in the black man Tanner renegade
no that's better than Road to Christ or
what was that yours no that was Max's
remember I always thinking his was uncle
sugar no those first rap name okay his
elementary school a Christian band was
road to Christ yeah okay so road to
Christ and Uncle sure guys want to make
sure that any listeners don't forget
these things about Max Weber yeah
yeah so you know but then like I kind of
fell out of music throughout middle
school until high school I started to
get back into it out of just a joke and
I had no idea what I was gonna do
outside of school honestly I was gonna I
was gonna join the Marines like how
everything in life made me feel like if
you put your mind to it you can be a
badass and I was like I'll just go be a
badass
I'll just go like in all those fails
I'll just still be the badass I'll just
go kill people I don't see what I'm a
trained killer and then you know and
then it'll be smooth sailing from there
still think about that option every now
and then too late now especially I don't
think they'll let me another I'm
diabetic
yeah to it on a potty it's like we
listen to this podcast it seems that you
lied about having diabetes exactly yeah
so that's something about that from time
to time but I fell into music
accidentally and then you know my path
through music has has redefined me as a
human it's allowed me to not only find
my passions artistically and figure out
that I am an artistic human but also has
helped redefine like my leadership
qualities and what I feel like I can do
with business because then I I started
to discover that I actually have a knack
for you know being an entrepreneur and
and then leading a business an
independent you know company right and
my dad is one of the you know best
businessmen that I know one of the best
men that I know in general like my dad
is such just a started from the bottom
built himself up from like you know
being from a poor broken home to working
from the machine shop to you know like
stay he stayed in the same industry
almost his entire life and went from you
know machine shop worker to VP of Sales
for like multiple states you know what I
mean and so he's just a self-made human
and so like that's inspirate that was
always inspiration to me and pushed me
but also me and him would butt heads a
lot because I'm not following the family
path you know what I mean like I'm
taking my own path to my own success but
it's also
in the music industry and how [__]
unrealistic is that right there's no
that caused so much like you know
trouble between us and my family and
like me my parents that really had like
a rocky relationship for a lot of years
a lot of that you know on my part and
you know so but now that they've seen
the perseverance and and and and the
fact that I'm not gonna take no for an
answer right now they're like all right
like I guess I guess you really are
gonna do this and so we've been able to
rekindle our relationship which is
obviously important yeah I saw over the
last few shows it's good to see em your
dad got me a beard yeah I love when
another man buys me a beer like that's
truthfully that's like man thank you I
know it's a beer but it's it's right
it's such a nice it's like a respect
thing yes I respect you it's it's it's
social like it's a head not like like
right cool right it's cool agreed so you
know as far as like the unbeatable
attitude like I feel like obviously I've
got a lot of inspiration for that seeing
my father's story and being a part of my
father's story but then also wanting to
prove that I can that I can pave my own
path in a completely different direction
and still like I always feel like to
certain extent I have something to prove
to that man you know I mean about me is
my own man right and so that's probably
been one of the bigger things is always
feeling like I needed to prove myself to
him and still do but where was that
going to fall into so like it happened
to fall into music and half life and the
business and all that you know what I
mean and all of my artistic endeavors
but because of all that and like losing
myself and having to refine myself and
like going off to college and my whole
like you know my whole party phase and
my whole drug phase and like all you
know like when when [__] was getting
really dark and then coming back out of
that and then realizing that I have to
grow up and if I'm going to actually do
all these things that I say I'm going to
I need to grow up and be a [__] man
and so because I feel like I went
through that darkness by myself and
transitioned out of some pretty low
points in my life that since I've come
from that what like nothing in this
earth can [__] stop me rarely not even
diabetes kids hey you don't I thought
you were ready for die but like diabetes
just came at you as you're running and
you're just like I don't see you let me
just put your hand up when you just said
all right right well that's the thing I
am in like so glad that it happened now
yeah not when I was like 20 really you
think you would have just ignored it at
20 or just holiday night past it and a
piece of [__] about it
yeah or victim maybe you know that's an
easy place to be when we have especially
with health scares you know it's it's a
dude when things come up and it's like
hey you've got to drastically change
everything about you like all the sudden
I mean the last thing you want to do is
drastically change everything about you
right like dude nobody wants to dress to
change everything about themselves but
sometimes health says you [__] got it
and a lot of times you can you can sit
on the ground and wallow for quite a
while you know and we all have our own
ways of doing I've had my own ways of
doing it in certain areas it's it's easy
to be the victim right but but dude I
think you're a good example of training
yourself man it's like you haven't
always been been this way it's like like
you have this unstoppable attitude but
there's also areas where you're like oh
this would happen
not too long ago I would have been
strong enough so having this constant
like believing in yourself every day in
some sort of ways leads yourself to when
you have something like a real health
thing come out you run ready for you're
strong for it you didn't even have to
like wallow for for ten weeks and then
like say okay now I'm gonna deal with it
right you know you're able to face it
head-on when you were like back in the
day when you're going through like high
school sports and stuff like how did
that how did those defeats like shape
you to be because you were saying that
like you took you took it kind of harder
back then like you didn't do you took it
more seriously lose in a wrestling match
it's tough but now it's like it doesn't
seem like failure is anything to you
like the there is a progression from who
you were then to know well also I mean a
lot of that comes with maturity a lot of
that comes with having a bigger scope of
understanding - that's like I said when
you're in high school and you take
sports very seriously and there's things
like state tournaments
there's nothing else that matters in the
world like you don't realize how big the
world is when you're in high school the
world revolves around high school it
revolves around the really a you know
and you know there's as much as I do
like That's Life that's life you know I
mean and then it's not until you bust
out into the world like I look at it
like everybody's like oh what happened
to like me telling all my friends we
were graduating that we're all gonna
still like kick it and you know what I
mean and it's because not that they were
they were not that they weren't your
friends but at the same time you guys
had to be at the same place at the same
time I look at it like it's raw right if
you picture high school like a straw
everybody's going through the same straw
we all have to be there so you hang out
with those people because you're there
and like that's all that matters the
drama in high school the sports the
relationships the loves the like that's
all that's all you know and that's life
and then when you graduate you hit the
end of the straw and all of a sudden
it's [__] free-for-all yeah and
everybody flies off into the wind like
those dandelions in the summertime you
know and original hours exactly yeah
exactly so that's kind of you know so
one I had to broaden my scope of the
world and that's why when I took off to
Seattle for like a year and a half yeah
yeah it got a real dark and real bad for
a while but that's because I went from
Kelso to Seattle right I went from you
know like you know what we doing this
week you know we're gonna you know find
some beers and yeah pull up in my pickup
truck drink some beers and then call it
good and that's wild you know what I
mean and then you go to college in
Seattle and it's like everybody's doing
drugs
yeah you're just exposed to you know
you're just exposed to a lot and it's
enticing it is enticing but it also you
got to be really really careful not to
lose yourself or be able to put yourself
back so like so that that be answer a to
that question is just like broadening my
scope of understanding and broadening
the scope of reality in what matters and
what does it matter as much right but
those defeats I took very hard because
that was all I know you know
like I was a returning state placer I
was supposed to place again except
higher and I ended up getting pins in
the match that would determine whether
or not you placed or not like at state
and it was like I put my whole and also
cutting weight I am now very against
high schoolers cutting weight or at
least the way the untrained uneducated
way that it happens I wearing a garbage
bag and running and [__] like that I
would love to like publicly speak on
this at some point like speak on the
dangers of like weight cutting and why
we should be at least teaching them how
to cut weight properly cuz like yeah
we're all spending so much time being
like ah like [__] everything except my
weight and losing a bunch of weight in
an unhealthy rapid manner so that I
could go like attempt to be strong after
making myself weak right and like and
then the fluctuations between after you
weigh in gaining a bunch of weight back
and like all this crazy in high school
that's [__] brutal your body is
supposed to be growing the most right
huh you know what I mean and so like I
spent all this time like just like like
putting my whole life into it cutting
away wrestling on the offseason all this
[__] for one week which is state the
week of state that's what all of those
months and years go into yeah so that
was like a devastating loss for me you
don't have me and so like it that took
me years to get over that and then I
realized the broader scope and that
handy to be focused on succeeding at
life and not succeeding in high school
right threat and then the whole music
thing happens and like people have have
hated the idea of me making it in music
and making music in general and like
I'll admit like yeah a lot of my early
stuff sucked a lot of my stuff sucks for
a long time right I was a cornball and I
fully accept that that's fine but like I
got so used to everybody especially my
hometown just hating me and do that like
despising what I do and talk and [__]
and this and that and like all this
petty stuff and then I go into like I go
to Seattle and all sudden it's like like
everybody's an artist and this is dope
vibe and nobody hates on you anymore I
don't know if it's just because like
it's so I think part of it is it's so
hard to see somebody that you knew as a
different
yeah be a different human it's very
difficult you know what I mean
especially maybe they feel like they
have not become a different human so to
see you become a different human it like
[__] Exim do to even allow room for
someone else to change it takes a shift
within the other people who are actually
it takes a shift within the onlookers
some people are not even willing to give
themselves a little bit of room to allow
you to change right and so they're like
I'm just gonna hold on to my opinion of
you but especially as you get you know
past the ages of the 21 22 years old you
definitely have to you know and again
for people in like a smaller town area
like arts there's you got to leave room
as an observer for change like you got
to be like oh I did think this through
this way about this person before but
like clearly they're changing clear they
I was incorrect about what I thought of
them or yeah or that mentality never
changes and then you just have to be
strong enough to know when you got to
cut people out of your life absolutely
like I started succeeding the most when
I told myself you know what nobody can
say anything to you that is going to
deter you discourage you bring you down
because you will never be anything and
if you want to succeed as bad as you
want to succeed you're going to cut
these people out of your life who do not
actually believe in you do not want to
see you change do not want to see you
grow do not want to see you succeed and
so I just stopped giving a flying [__]
about what anybody thinks I can or
cannot do and then all sudden I make
that change and then [__] starts
happening right and then all sudden that
synchronicity that energy started
balling up inside of me and I started to
see that manifest success into my life
and now I don't give a [__] I don't care
I don't care what you think about me I
don't and and that's not even me being
arrogant that's like if like I am all
for like if you want to show love or
like if you like you know if there's old
relationships in my past that want to
sit down have a beer and rekindle I'm
all for it I'm not an arrogant person
I'm doing that right on being [__] on
right or at least I'll go down that to
affect my mentality right so that's and
then that just snowballs people don't
understand when you start to empower
yourself and like you know the whole
like half the reason that I'm doing all
this is just to prove to people that
empowering yourself
real that you can empower yourself and
you can change I mean [__] that's less
you know half stands for hope and
mission fortitude the whole part of it
was to be like if you want whatever you
want to do in life you can achieve that
with basically these three key aspects
and you can you can use hope ambition
fortitude to like propel yourself into
something greater a greater version of
you right that's what I'm out here doing
and so slowly but surely it's starting
to actually work and so like once you
start to empower yourself then you build
on that energy and then that energy
snowballs and snowballs and then you get
to that level that you were talking
about of like an undefeatable mindset
yeah like I've just you just have to
start but that's only gonna start within
yourself when you make that decision
that you're that you're going to to cut
off that negativity and truly focus on
yourself and believe in yourself more
than you ever have and it'll be hard at
first and it'll get easier it'll get
easier and then you'll start attracting
more positive people into your life and
those people that's that's the real
issue Pro we were talking about we
talked about two books before this - one
of them you're talking about
synchronicity that word man I mean
that's that's some real [__] that's a
lot of times people be like hey how's it
going - podcast house or whatever I'm
like bro honestly I'm following my
intuition and the synchronicities aren't
lining up I am I'm doing what I feel is
right and I'm ignoring like you like
you're talking about it's almost like
you put your blinders on in what I'm
focused on is me and it might sound
selfish but I'm focused on like what I'm
supposed to be doing right like I like
oh if you don't like what I'm doing like
okay like right you don't even cross my
mind like I'm just right past you you
can't affect me if I and I think that
when you start going on that road once
you have your blinders on you get to
where you like you're going 70 miles per
hour towards your goals in like like you
might [__] switch lanes once in a
while but it seems like the the the
synchronicities just start it's like
it's like you tune into who you really
are and who you truly believe yourself
to be and then all of a sudden like
people and things and opportunities
start popping up like it's almost
[__] magic man and I start coming up
but it's it's it's a it's a simple thing
but you can kind of think of like say
you your daughter you got a daughter and
she's turning 16 soon and you're looking
for cars for
and you know all she wants is a red
Honda Civic and then all of a sudden
like you don't see red Honda Civics but
then all the sudden read how the sexes
are [__] everywhere because you're
like you're looking out for me because
it's a reliable car for my daughter is
this actually a car that I want to get
hair like oh you know that one's
actually not too bad
I like those rims like what would she
like you know you start your mind starts
warping around I know I want to get my
daughter a car and she likes red Honda
Civics so all of a sudden you see red
Honda Civics everywhere this is this is
you know the synchronicity I want you to
don't be afraid to like you know we live
in a world where we're afraid to say
things at me anyway like oh I don't want
to get to tinfoil hat or to woowoo
or to you know talking about intuition
and in mystical sort of things that we
don't they're hard to conceptualize into
words but I've totally believed in them
and I think that exploring them and
expanding them as creators is [__]
awesome so tell me Ryan Reid about
synchronicity manifestation talk to me
about this [__] bro so first and
foremost I am not religious I I am you
know I work very hard to be very open
minded I don't care what you believe in
it you know like that I'm not gonna
judge you based on what you believe in
obviously unless it's you know unless
there's a piece of [__] and believe in
piece of [__] philosophies but like you
know I don't hide that just me
personally I personally am not really
just I personally don't believe that
there is a God and I hope people don't
judge me for that but if they do yeah
whatever it's your opinion man exactly
I'm not gonna judge you back you know so
why are you interested me but anyway
plumbing is that I that so energy is
what I believe in like I believe that
each human is a product of what they
like a product of their own
consciousness and like the energies that
they begin we're almost like all like
magnets you know or you could look at it
like the the two wolves theory where the
the the grandpa was like tells the
grandson that there's two wolves and all
of us one of them is greed lust
anger agony all that and then the other
one is peacefulness selflessness hair
love all that good stuff and then the
grand sounds like well which one wins or
yeah because he was like the two wolves
are always at battle they're always
battling each other inside of you
instead of every person and the grand
sounds like well which one wins and the
Graham the grandfather's like the one
you feed you know and so like I'm a big
fan of that or like so Jim Morrison of
the doors who I'm a big fan of got me
into Frederick Nietzsche and then so in
the birth of tragedy there is the whole
Apollonian Dionysian concept where we
all live somewhere on this this like
balance beam of our Apollonian sad and
our die nice the inside and that's
that's not as like polar ring as the
wolves but same kind of concept where
one is like more so I guess you could
say matters of like the heart and then
the other and then the Apollonius has
more matters that like the brain so it'd
be like intellect kind of versus emotion
right and we all live on this balance
and so actually have a song called
Apollonian and ICN that kind of speaks
on that topic a little bit and kind of
the struggles in my mind with my own
balance and so like what I believe is
that inside of everybody is basically
this balance beam of energy and what you
put your weight into is what is going to
win if it end yeah and basically once
you realize that that power is yours
like that balance once you reel and
that's that's the hardest part the
hardest part about my whole idea and
philosophy on like the human being is
realizing is knowing once you know that
you're in control of your own balance
being right then you start to naturally
become less victim minded and more
ambition minded and then you start to
notice the way the energies revolve
around you what energies you're
attracting and what energies are giving
out because like what you said when you
put your blinders on you start speeding
down the freeway and then you said that
like people and opportunities and things
pop up more often than not those people
that start popping up are going to be
because they share a similar energy to
you right so then I'm just
like connecting my energies with the
right people instead of trying to butt
heads connecting my energies to the
wrong people and the wrong energies and
so I'm building this like network of
energies with the people that vibe with
me on my wavelength and therefore that
is making my energy stronger exactly an
or darker depending on what you feed you
don't mean so that's kind of my whole
philosophy about because here's a deal
do I know for a fact that there is no
God no no no anybody know that's the
point nobody does what happens when you
die speculation nobody knows except
people that are dead and good luck
asking that Brett right so like I don't
base it off of like this is truth and
this is fact i base it off what can I
use like what what applies to me and
what can I use to not only better myself
but better those around me and for me
it's that energy concepts you know I
mean and that's just personifying it you
know maybe it's energy maybe it's the
Holy Spirit whatever it is you know we
get whatever word doesn't matter we're
talking about the same thing because
exactly you know and ideally like here's
the other thing too is it's gonna suck
if there is a god and and he's like he's
like well you know cuz based on certain
aspects of the Bible he would be like
what and Christians are probably and
crucify me for this no pun intended
hey but um you know you know they're
like there's something about like oh you
deny me in front of your friends Elton I
even for my father and so it's gonna be
real shitty if I die and and this is
years down the past after years of my
like the the philanthropic I believe I
pronounced that right the fear the
philanthropic side of me that I want to
ya the act of philanthropy right maybe
your philanthropic ambitions thank you
is how you would say that I love it
somebody's gonna be like no that wasn't
right but so I I do want to do a lot of
philanthropy in my life you know what I
mean like with these benefit concerts
each one continues to get bigger and
like I really do want to help change
lives for the better I want to make a
difference right and it's gonna be super
hypocritical pretty shitty for me if I
do all this philanthropy and like do and
then help a lot of people in life and
then I get to heaven
and he's like well even though you were
a really good dude and like helped a lot
of people you technically didn't believe
in God so and then trap door opens and I
dropped down the hell yeah that's gonna
suck but that's the if that's if that's
what it is that's the mean you're the
only one who's dealing with that if
that's if that's the reality that people
think is real then you're the only one
who has to pay for it right I mean like
you know so exactly so I you know right
because nobody else is gonna know what's
going on yeah so you know that's that's
me that's I'm I'm very energy driven I
was I told you this before but when I
read synchronicity and when I read the
war of art not to be confused with the
art of war when I read those two books I
was actually in work-release jail for
some other dumb stuff that we don't
gotta get into you know I was I was an
idiot back in the day like around like
between like night with all big boys my
friend we're I've been boys and I got
sometimes right I got a lot of trouble
like personally in like legal trouble
when I was like 19 to like 22 you know
and that really helped shape me a lot
but so anyway I read those two books
when I was in there and that was like
you know when you have nothing else to
do you really fully dive into the book
because you don't have distractions
around you obviously and so like those
were key to me starting to build this
mentality that I do and this belief
system that I do of the energies you
attract and the energies that you put
effort into right dude do you think I
personally believe that a book I mean
anything can change your life like dude
someone farting too close next you can
change a life if that's the opportunity
you're ready for but I really believe
that a book can change someone's life
like like very quickly like you know I
listened to a lot of podcasts I've seen
plenty of episodes of Parks and Rec in
the office and stuff and as much as they
bring me joy none of them have ever
profoundly changed my life and like
sparked something in me that I didn't
know was even there ready to be sparked
I think that a book not just like a book
has magic or anything but I think that
just slowing down this crazy-ass world
and in reading or audiobook or whatever
is enough to like kind of bring us out
of our fast momentum our maze that we
all have to live in
and really like spark something that's
already already within us um do you like
you
I mean you're pretty busy with your half
stuff but have you recently in the last
year at any good books outside we talked
about the war of art and then I
synchronicities and so that's actually
funny that you say that because we just
Carissa and I we just put down six books
each and whoever whoever gets through
them first the the loser has to buy both
of us Apple watches that's so savage
holy [__] right because that's like
that's like a bunch of money on the line
you're hacking the human [__] meat
Batman like this right because obviously
you want an Apple watch don't you yeah
you're gonna have to read a bunch of
books right next of them and they're all
not like I don't read fiction not
because I don't want to but because I
have so little time to read at all that
I want it to be yeah you know I want it
to be something that I'm gonna take with
me right empowering right and so I'll
tell you what I got in the works right
now I'm about a third of the way through
the seven Habits of Highly successful
humans and highly-effective paper yeah
that one yeah Highly Effective People
about like a third of the way into that
that book actually changed my life photo
straighter dude
it's changing my life currently yeah so
that's amazing that's a good one I made
it like halfway through the 50 laws of
power or 48 laws of power can I have it
read though and it's good it's a lot
like that's the thing is like there's
all these side stories and everything
and like you kind of gotta like filter
through the 48 laws of power because
it's it's really manipulative too and
like you'd want to be that guy right you
don't I mean like it's almost when those
books were it's like if I implement all
these like I'm gonna be a low-key kind
of a piece of [__] like yeah I'm gonna
watch my own narcissism yeah it's gonna
it's gonna like you know give you tips
on basically how to step on people to
get your self further and that's not my
mo I don't want to do the crabs in the
bucket you know maybe it's good to learn
about so you watch out for that sort of
thing it can make you defensive it could
be a sword or it could be the shield
alright so I'm gonna I'm gonna finish
reading it for the fact of it being a
shield so there's that one I'm reading
this book called who's afraid of AI
and that's a really quick one and that
one's really dope it's funny because it
was written in like late 2018 and I'm
like [__] this is already outdated
because I move so fast everything about
AI is so different from 2018
like but it's dope because it really
looks at like how jobs are going to
change and like how there's a lot of
aspects of AI that we don't realize are
already in place like there's a lot of
jobs that are using them and a lot of
areas of the workforce that use it
heavily that you don't even think about
first things you think about our cars I
Robot an Elon Musk you know what I mean
and I've worked and I've worked in a
production mills before so I definitely
like fresh in my mind I'm like these
people are not gonna job right pretty
soon so another one you might like so
that was interesting also if you're
interested in AI Andrew Yang's
Joe Rogan podcast I'll fair Gideon money
money money um no pun intended because
he wants to everyone again I love
learning but yeah I do want to
eventually get somebody who's pretty
good at AI on here we go just I really
like explaining to people who don't have
any idea with [__] going on right I
want to get somebody can be like that
let me give you just some four one one
on my count under stones are you
familiar with neural ink
yeah half row oh my god how is this even
reality
dude the fact that wait wait give it's
for somebody who's never heard the term
neural link before give him a low low
down is a quick tip there's okay so
quickly there's two aspects to neural
link there's the short term goals and
there's the long term goals short term
and girl goals very humanitarian very
amazing like absolutely the long-term
goals scare the [__] out of me
so Elon Musk comes up for this key
presentation talk to the front of it and
Elon Musk
goes on like a keynote speech and he's
like alright so we have this neural link
and basically we are going to take
microscopic wires wire them into your
neurons via the back of your ear and
then you'll have a transmitter that will
like clip on to that that connection to
your neurons and then it will basically
be able to read the the movements
between like your synapses it'll be able
to read that just as quickly as your
brain reads
and then it'll basically so the short
term goal is if you're like like a
paraplegic as we advanced in prosthetics
you would be able to so basically it
makes your mind a Bluetooth device so
you could have like a prosthetic leg and
be able to move it in the same way that
you tell your muscles to move through
your brain but via like almost like a
Bluetooth connection so he's trying to
basically eliminate paralyzation which
is if that was the right way to say that
word which is amazing it's fantastic
right yeah but then there's the other
side of it where he's like but then the
long-term I want everybody on a genius
super cloud yeah so basically like Siri
would be in your head like you know it'd
be like Ironman where it's like Oh what
are we in the nervous yeah and Jarvis
yeah I'd be like that but it's like dude
if somebody hacked iCloud how long is it
before they hack the genius super cloud
with all of our [__] brains attached
to it I hate or how long is it before
the military actually not even how long
military is already getting on Elon
Musk's ass so how can we weaponize this
right they probably we are we already
probably got a chip in our head that's
so small it's like we're just talking
about this Elon thing like ants the size
of your finger right it's already way
smaller right it's like yeah who got
their flu shot this year well you got a
super chip you got the nanobots to the
nanobot right so like the long-term the
long-term goals are pretty scary for
neural link and it's really you know
exciting to read into but then you know
at the same time the other half of the
coin is you're like oh you know this was
like a year ago and so you're like okay
that sounds really interesting but
obviously that's gotta be like a couple
years out or whatever right like calm
down Elon like I get it you're ambitious
and then he's like oh so we've already
been successful with monkeys yep we've
already had a monkey control a computer
wirelessly through his neural link food
so you create a plan of the Apes so
that's cool
yeah that's here for now great
terminator and already it is here dude
let's start human trials in 2020 and
then also you wake up like a month and a
half ago and is 2020 yeah it's is now
yeah yeah it's weird that it's like
we're still live in our life's doing
like
whatever and like there's [__]
doing that right now making Silicon
Valley wherever they're at like their
this happening right now it's so dope
it's fascinating it's terrifying but
it's fascinating and [__] awesome
right it's a wild ass time to be alive
you were on the third book of your six
oh right right um so oh one that I won
that doesn't include this that's not
included in the six actually there's two
that not included in the six mention mob
books grab a brief history of Vice who
advise a vice okay it's it's really it's
not like a life-changing book but it's
really fun and really interesting it
basically looks at the bird like the the
the oldest human history known of like
all vice and that goes from drinking to
drugs to [__] talking to sex - oh shoot
like oh like music like how the
Stonehenge is there's this huge theory
that Stonehenge was this this musical
arena like the world's first rave
because it's it's it's the way that it's
put together can if you get enough
people drumming at a certain frequency
like in Stonehenge the way it reflects
creates this like trance this rhythmic
trance and people would just like resume
at this frequency as a perfect that
there's a proven science between like
certain frequencies in the way they make
your your mind kind of react and so
there's a we can dive into frequencies I
make beats and [__] to just like you I
probably had some [__] up dates or
you're like I touched some weird
frequencies today when I was making so I
would do a trade 0 dude I've had days
where I like my legs feel hella weird
the rest of day cuz I'm like I don't
know what the [__] but I was doing but I
was in that frequency too long when I
was making that thing and I feel [__]
up or in it yeah it's definitely so
there's that so you might find that one
interesting but yeah then the funny
thing too is is he teaches you like how
to do a lot of these early like like for
instance like the first type of beer
that was discovered by man and like then
he'll give you like
directions ik step-by-step recipes on
how to do it or like there's like this
hallucinogen made from like like some
sort of cheese and mushrooms and he
teaches you how to sounds like a wild
ride yeah so he teaches he's like but
but you have to you have to fast for a
week before you do it and he'll do it in
The Hague so here were my results like
he was in the nest it's that one's
really interesting brief history events
interesting and I do like stuff that
were people guinea pig themselves on the
top right and that's kind of like what I
do so
okay yes exactly so you probably enjoy
that one I'm have you read who moved my
cheese I've not read who movements you
could read it in a day it's really small
and it's all about being willing to
change and adapt ooh yeah it uses this
whole metaphor and again you could read
in a day but so it's it's a quick one
but it's this whole metaphor of like
you're a cheese or you're a mouse and a
maze and somebody moves your cheese and
based on your habits one of the mice
stays and waits for it to come back the
other mice the other Mouse steps out
into the unknown into the maze knowing
that it and it's gonna have to adapt and
to survive and find more cheese it is
the long played out metaphor well this
sounds great because I actually like
Shaylee and I talk about a lot of times
like trying to conceptualize the way
that my mind works is a lot of times
well in helping other people is getting
them to realize like you're in the maze
like so today I might find interest in
that just cuz a lot of times we're
trying to solve our maze problems we're
trying to like is it left or is it right
but the truth is you need to just notice
that you're in the maze right nuts
that's what's gonna tell you if it's
left or right or yeah remove yourself
from anyone who wants like a real quick
just kick in the ass about being more
open and accepting to change who moved
my cheese real quick love it yeah so the
three that I'm currently reading though
were 48 laws of power the Who's Afraid a
I and seven Habits of Highly Effective
humans right that's yeah yeah the right
title what were the other three um oh
man hopefully I can I can remember
they're all like stacked up on top of
each other I know I'm always like I'm a
third away this one through I'm 1/8 of
the way of the two that right
yes I've even started three of them I
don't even remember what they're called
right now so well maybe we'll get the
review on the next Ryan Reid fun right
exactly
um so we want to okay so I want to talk
about creativity and producing and I
want to talk to producer Ryan Wade for
sure I'm in rapper Ryan Reed of course
too but I do just want to on the seven
Habits of Highly Effective People just
because it's a cool so there's a story
in that I'm probably gonna butcher it
but I think it might be the opening
story about they're on the train they're
on the subway and there's kids that are
like like acting out do you remember
having gone to this part yet wasn't it a
party or there was like the the the like
birthday party and the kid didn't want
to share the toys was a bad story you
know it's a difference where okay so
I'll tell story I might butcher it so
read this book seven Habits of Highly
Effective People because he brings a
bunch of like I metaphoric child stories
I thought it was at the beginning but I
haven't read it in a long time so
essentially this dude is on a subway or
train and he's like at the end of his
work today and essentially he has like a
couple kids and a guy next to him and
the kids are just being loud they're
being like kind of naughty they're just
like not behaving and they're getting
progressively louder and like disturbing
his peace and he talks about how he's
like he starts to get a little more
frustrated Aneesa I'm gonna say
something to this guy I'm gonna tell him
I'm gonna be like hey can you I'm like
tell him he's watches kids right and so
he gets he gets to the nerd he talks
about socks and fell through it in his
head and then he says all right I
wouldn't get the nerve and he's finally
goes hey man can you can you watch your
kids they're they're acting out you know
that they're being naughty or what
they're disturbing the peace whatever he
says to him and the guy kind of snaps
out of it the father and he looks around
he's like oh no I'm I'm very sorry sir
you know I guess they're probably just a
little out of you know they're they're
probably really don't know how to act
because we just left the hospital and
their mother just died right yep and
it's like dude I remember reading that
and I was like holy for my heart drop
and I was like it like woke up this
thing in me and also holy [__] we could
be so caught up and like I'm gonna say
something I'm gonna like we were
thinking about ourselves so [__] much
in these situations like you're
disturbing my peace we don't really
think about like this man is just
staring off into space you think he's
not being good dad but he's actually
just going through one most traumatic
suffering experiences he's absolutely
and the kids kids don't just just cry
and like understand that the severity
the things that happened to him they act
out they be kids they don't know what's
going on you know so I'm bidding ways so
that I remember when I read that that
like profoundly changed me and I could
have been remembering that a little
incorrectly so it's definitely read that
book reader but it's actually I remember
the apartment of mine and that's pretty
yeah you pretty much nailed it obviously
you know I think it's important to see
other people and you know you can't just
walk around like like if there's some
dude just punching random people in the
face you came like he's probably having
his mob just dad you know I mean let's
balance - yeah there's a bit but I think
that when you can see people immediately
for like the first thing you see is like
they've got something there's a reason
that's going on Ryan they've got
something
but yeah so great book seven Habits
highly affected people let's move on to
Ryan Reid the producer yeah hi
personally I so I've been like a DJ I've
been a DJ for many years and we've
worked together DJ wise I've always kind
of pushed away the I've not had a lot of
self-confidence in like the producing
side of the world I honestly just
haven't really done a ton of producing
I'm the guy who was stuck in many years
of just like watching every tutorial I
could possibly find and not [__]
putting a beat pad under my fingers and
just doing it right the last two years I
have done more of that I've started
playing piano more started like allowing
myself to - I don't know just make some
[__] I'm not not really for any any
other reason but other than myself but
yeah it's a really cool journey and I
know that over the years you have
definitely gotten more and more great at
producing
in in you inspire me and I just want to
talk about producing yeah tell me how
did you when it first started so like
rapping of course but when did you when
did you branch into like making your own
beats or like explain your own sounds
almost immediately almost immediate they
started about the same time okay I just
did not explains a lot right I did I
just didn't I didn't put out I didn't
put out the ones that I produced for
myself for a while you know what I mean
it was always something that I here's
the deal if you want the secret just
suck for a bit yeah
like you're just gonna have to go
through that period of
not like making a bunch of beats that
aren't great right you don't a meme and
so I didn't even release most the ones
that I made myself I did some like in
high school I released a couple but I
ended up linking up with a couple people
who were just naturally way better than
I was at producing like some just some
local cats and so I started using their
beats and I just I you know I didn't
really have the balls to like really
like make mine the the highlight of my
work until years later until like 20
probably like 2014 Max and I we did a
whole collaboration EP called the you
know rap EP and we produced every beat
on that and we made it a goal to like
it's gonna be all of our own production
right but that was also when we started
linking with Matt Jefferson aka make
music or Die
aka crumb bum who is he said God like we
call him jefe that got because that dude
is he's 12 years self-taught engineering
actually more than twelve now
self-taught engineering producing he's
toured the US as the lead singer of
mortified mortician which think like
Marilyn Manson style he plays guitar
drums bass I think the dude is just a
legend and he's become we start working
he's out of Black Diamond right right oh
yeah you know you know it I got totally
I always forget I know yeah will do
because we haven't really worked
together at that suit like I have it I
don't think I've seen you there
what cuz I don't work we don't work
there yeah what one no but you just
saying you think that our paths would
cross in that way but I've never had
they didn't cross it yeah I've been
having in years though like we just do I
just do it on his house yeah you know
and like he's become like he's become
like a big brother to me
in in a lot of ways music and just life
mmm like that dudes just that's my big
bro and I mean [__] even he was one of
the only people that I told that I was
in the hospital because it was creeping
up on studio day and I'm like hey they
keep telling me I'm here so I'm probably
not gonna get like how I'm supposed to
be let out and then they kept me another
day I'm supposed to be let out
sounds like dude like I'm probably not
gonna get let out till tomorrow which
the day of my studio so I was like dude
I'm just gonna come straight from the
hospital to the studio so we could still
get this song recorded and we did and I
want to go into that too but he met
cheeks out in the nightgown or what you
just in the studio just right I kept the
gun I'm like I ain't even changed put
the video on right exactly but so he VIN
like he ended up buying a MIDI key like
a mini MIDI keyboard because he had the
idea he wanted a smaller one anyway but
he he had no reason to actually go do it
I told him I was in the hospital he went
into Guitar Center and bought a mini
MIDI keyboard brought that and
headphones to the hospital and was like
hey so maybe you could at least produce
while you're stuck in here boy and I was
like dude I was like three beats that
like are all bangers like yeah yeah it's
amazing man is so cool and like you know
I'm in like the 14th story of OHSU which
is up on the the hill up on the
mountains and I just have this whole
pretty like my whole window is just
Portland we can you see PCT mountains
from there yeah I mean towards Mount
Hood dude I love that we there's so many
great like top story views like 14th
floor
where we live you can just look around
most the time you can catch a mountain
if there's not any hills next it's over
and so I had like a big window shelf and
so I just literally set it up on the
shelf up against the window yes I would
just produce and just look in there's
nuts but so that just speaks to the type
of dude he is but working with him for
so long I've been able to progress so
much you know because like I'll take my
beats and then I'll bounce out the track
outs individually and then he uses his
engineering skills with all the plugins
in the south the the you know editing
plugins that I do not have the money for
and just makes everything sound better
so mean him together of just like like
evolutionized my abilities do like what
we're capable of doing right and then so
now like I just need the raw bare bones
and then make sure I write to it and
then bounce it out and then we go to him
and I'm like can you help me like you
know I in my head it sounds like you
know do to do but in reality is like do
to do so let anything like that's just a
stupid example but you know so he just
helps me take all of my babies and turn
them
two grown men make it make sense yeah
and so less people like that right and
so that's but that's also helped me
learn how to come you know prepared with
like more in-depth full projects you
know because now I'm getting the hang of
it and so now I I produce everything
that I I make you know mean since like
twenty
I don't know sixteen or some it's 2015
is waiting what's your preferred uh so I
I arrange and logic but I use a machine
a lot okay but I don't like the
arrangement and machine it's just not my
style I hate how it arranges so I love
arranging and logic it's just what I
know I've been on Logic since I was like
in high school right and so like I just
arranged on that and then like I don't
know if you're familiar with output and
like arcade I use the output arcade all
time row oh my like and you know there's
a secret weapon and you know what [__]
the people that say that that's cheating
and that derail fight that [__] makes me
cancel that [__] makes me I'm a DJ so I
feel like I'm like yeah I mean I've been
using loops and samples literally I've
been getting hella money by using loops
and samples so like yeah you're talking
about so like honestly like oh I'll use
you know a lot of times I'll still make
my own drums piece by piece with my
machine you know I'll still drum it out
and then a lot of times I'll still use
my own like keys and stuff and but the
fact that you can match key signatures
for all the difference
like like engines in an arcade like all
I need is one that like gets an idea
started way to freeze your ideas that's
my favorite thing about that program
because you can you can drag into and it
changes the key for you like that's the
biggest thing is like when you like I
got this dope ID and you start playing
drums and your drums are out of key and
you're like why the [__] does that sound
right not how it should sound in my head
or vocal sample to a guitar sample you
know the ability to just make them to
lock in that key signature and in what
we're talking about listeners if you
don't know we're talking about we're
talking about everything that if every
sound has a key it has a key in a tempo
and you can what what a what a DJ or or
what a producer or what someone who's
mixing things together they make them
all in the same
key they put them together so they
actually sound good so just because I
have a cool like dududu and then I have
a cool bum bubble bum doesn't mean
they're in the same key doesn't mean
they go together it doesn't mean at the
same tempo right so making those things
actually make sense together is is the
art of producing and mixing in these
things well and that's I would say one
of the biggest smartest things that I
did to elevate my production is learn
key signatures right like where I'm at
yeah and like so the thing is is like I
can't sit down on your piano and bust
out like a memorized Beethoven song or
even a memorized journey song like I I
don't have any songs memorized that I
can impress you with but I understand
key signatures so I could be like oh
here's a G minor chord and here's C
minor and so that allows me to produce
like I'll produce a melody and then by
the time I move on from the piano melody
and move on to the drums and the other
aspects and then I write lyrics to it
and then I record it and then worry
about engineering like mixing it and
then I release it and I'm worried about
promo I forgot that [__] I can't sit
down and play this beautiful piano
melody that I wrote one time yeah
because I didn't memorize it I didn't
take the time to because there's so much
other aspects to do so like
understanding how music works and
understanding theory like I would say
for anybody that wants to produce or
even be an artist take time to
understand music theory like it's
important and something on YouTube I
wish that I wish that I had started the
journey earlier that I did because I
don't have any any sort of musical
background it which I think [__]
every song is cool I love all songs I
just want to mix them together and
that's like my music background is that
YouTube University YouTube University I
no doubt there's so much learn who you
watch on YouTube like you have any like
beat makers on YouTube like I usually
use YouTube super specifically right
like how to use this VST yeah it's like
I'll come in or like I'll come into a
question of like so if I wanted to yeah
like if it's like okay I need to
automate some pitch on like an intro to
like make the vocal sample go you know
from this octave slowly to this octave
every quarter note before I rap
I'll be like how to do how to automate a
pitch you know on Logic Pro it's like
very specific [__]
yeah or I'll be like a lot of times
though Google key signatures cuz I'll
forget all right how many flats are in
you know B minor or whatever but as far
as the ones that I actually watch I
watched a lot of the genius ones
actually there's genius and then there's
one other one that are like popular
beats because I like to hear how the the
popular radio ones were made right
because then I can like kind of like
pick up on like things that sonically
make it a successful record right right
right right but bow too right but yeah I
just sucked for a long time you know I
mean and then all of a sudden I made
enough to where they started to not suck
or and then arcade was able to just like
blow my mind with like the the the sound
starters like for instance tornado my
most popular song right now it very
quickly became a most popular song
because it's fun and it's not like deep
and dark like a lot of my stuff but like
instantly
I found that like for those that have
heard tornado you know that that first
like I owe that sample that vocal sample
I found that unlike instantly I'm like
that dude it sent you like on a
projection like this is the idea go from
there and it's just - it's the the
initial like that I I hear
and then the oh I just put those
together then there was the one that was
like I don't want nothing those together
and I was like that's Helene 808 and
there's the beat so do you like loop net
so you start out with your idea just the
creative process we start with your idea
you're like okay that's the one it gets
you going you have this thought okay I
think we can go with this and then you
just like follow the intuition of
throwing some [__] some drums in the
beat pad and just yes what happens it
depends on the song cuz like for
instance like there was a hook that I
made the other day no no baby did you
get what you came for you played me no
you crying on the same floor you said
let you down reminisce you're not in
Flex you play the whole town on you did
it like and like she played the whole
tournament in yeah and it's like but no
one's left around or no but it came
crashing down and no one's left around
and that's um truth that you can't drown
on and it's like it's pretty dark it's
pretty deep but I came up with that
first and like I'm not a singer by any
means but I can hear the cadence in my
head so then I gotta find it like
sometimes I start with the you know so
it was like baby did you get what you
came for and so I'm on there like dddd
that pop I do do I'm not gonna find it
cuz you know I'm not a singer but I can
like here at cadence and I can replicate
it you know or light with your fingers
yes is a note right yes no that's the
note or like what we did with that
particular song is that like made the
beat and then I went to Matt Jefferson
and I was like can you help me can you
like while I was trying to record it I
was like can you like have that play on
a piano like even if it's not part of
the me just add them the melody on piano
right I can sing along to it and and
know which pitches I'm supposed to go
for you can almost hook your voice to
the melody of the piano right stay on
that because this is my melody and I
just I don't know how to like do it good
enough without hearing it being played
because I understand what I am and I
understand what I'm not I understand
that I'm an artist I'm a musician I
produce and I rap I don't sing it's just
not you know what I mean so I had to
figure out how to be it's almost like
one of my favorite inspirations
production and artist wise is Mac Miller
and we could get into Mac Miller a lot
but the biggest thing you have to
realize is the change from like kids
it's a blue slide park - good a.m. - My
Beautiful Dark Twisted
that's Kanye Divine Feminine yeah -
swimming and like he he's you know
similar to me in the sense that he's a
producer he's a rapper he has music
inside of him he's an artist but he's
not a singer but he figured out how to
still create emotion and not a rapper
but an artist like if you look at that
progression especially from good a.m. to
Divine Feminine to swimming he became an
artist I'm as I like to look at when
you're not a singer when you're like
okay I know I don't have the Beyonce but
right but my lyrics and my mouth my
voice and those are instruments right I
got to learn how to get a little better
at using each of those instruments every
single day if you treat him as like a
it's not like me like I'm the singer but
like these are things that come out of
my head in my mouth and I use them as
instruments in the mix yeah that's like
that's like that's it that's how Mac
Miller writes you dude the dude's got so
much
up and down like he said I mean not I
guess he is a specific genre right of
his own but he's but those last two
records real started to just so Dianna
right and he realized that he's you know
that's why I relate with him so much is
because he figured out how to be a great
musician without being a good singer you
know what I mean
bruh what what did you start in the rail
here what how did you how did you feel
any past man I I I genuinely had it was
this moment where I was like I didn't
realize that like yeah I see him on
Twitter I listened to his music but like
I feel closer to this dude then I feel
to a lot of my friends like I like I
felt genuinely disheartened when he died
and I'm not trying to make it about me
by any means but I think that the
Internet and social media and like
connection for a lot of artists brings
us closer like if what I'm saying is I
think it feels like a home he died when
he passed do you remember like what
happened when it when the news came
across uh yes so I was like a decent Mac
Miller fan like I'm not I'm not gonna
sit well I I was used to be a decent
Magna fan like pre Divine Feminine right
I was like the casual Mac Miller fan and
so like I'm not I'm not gonna say like
I've been right or died forever yeah you
don't have to feel nothing but like
after good am like Divine Feminine and
swimming like Divine Feminine is if I
had to pick one Mac Miller album that
meant the most to me it wasn't that one
and that's because the the darkness he
traveled through and like the breakups
and stuff and I was going through I was
going through a long time like a long
term up-and-down relationship with
somebody from like high school uh-huh
right that continued to be up and down
throughout like you know 20 I don't know
like 15 16 maybe I don't recall exactly
my years and write a lot of years of
like knowing somebody and like knowing
the toxicity versus the love and that
you know crazy balance that a lot of us
had been involved in right and like Mac
Miller's album Divine Feminine was like
me at that
time and like so it was it was written
for me you know when you hear those
albums and they're like I feel like they
wrote that about me and that's why it
felt like a home he died because you
relate to their like what they're going
through that I feel like you went
through that with them and then you feel
in turn that they went through your
struggles with you so yeah you guys have
like it's like a big bro like who just
he had like the same path as you and
you're like holy [__] what you're able
to conceptualize us into your words into
your lyrics and like loudly to process
what I didn't even know it's processing
like your words they your your words
gave explanation to the things that my
body was going through my decipher yeah
so like connection so define feminine
happens and I fell in love with it and
fell in love with him and his music and
then swimming happens and it was even so
then it was even more ladders what's the
years what's your favorite track off
swimming oh okay well okay so the the
intro record like when he's like I just
need a way out of my head I'd do
anything for a way out of my head like
that chills when you said that right
thanks to me so much but or there's
there's another one that like meant a
lot to me more recently and that was
conversations part one because he was
like for one that Cadence's his bass
line is good too right and the way his
cadence rides but when he was like like
he talks about like sit around the house
do getting faded like homie that a
entertain me like going I forget the
exact lyrics but it's basically like you
know it was basically like I need to get
like it really really put into
perspective all the time I've wasted you
know and so that one hit me more after
he died
so by the way when he died after like
how close I felt to swimming in Divine
Feminine like I was devastated how is
you know what I mean and I was really
the only one of my team that really
listened to him mm-hmm and so like it
was it was a lot for me personally and
because I kind of had my own path with
Mac Miller that I didn't really share
with other people like a lot of
[__] had that right
feel like like for me I've always loved
Mac Miller breath like it was a silent
love like it was like a I was crowd was
connected to that dude in a lot more
ways he realized you were connected yeah
if you weren't you were just like casual
it's like it's like do-or-die with Mac
Miller right and so I at that point I
was really strong with him so it hurt
and then I ended up going taking off for
my birthday for like a weekend and we
just made music it was me honest and
Krista this was you know a couple years
ago and we took off to Prineville for my
birthday and we were at this guest house
and this huge guest house and I turned
the whole big dining room table into a
studio I brought all of my [__] and we
just we didn't even go to the lake we
went to Lake like one time we made music
and drank and chilled and it was so
genuine like we just spent all the time
but like in my heart like that was like
right after the passing and I just I
felt like I was traveling down a very
similar path you know mentally and then
like with our both of our like struggles
with not wanting to be sober you know
and like the lack of desire for sobriety
and written so I traveled down the the
sobriety path with him to or lack
thereof and so like I just all weekend
in that music or like in in that vibe
you know Carissa was she end up saying
someone she was like she was like I
asked him to I asked him to look over
you last night like it was you know and
so because she I think she visualized
the same lifestyle for me right and so
she was like yeah I asked him last night
after he passed she was like I asked him
last night to look over you you don't
find you don't fall into the same path
did you start bawling your eyes out what
you said that cuz I think I'm right
whatever
right now yeah you know that's just
powerful in and so but yeah then then
I'd be listening to conversations
afterwards after his death and you know
it'd be like you just behind around the
house you getting wasted that ain't
entertainment like get up and go and
make it whatever the executives are and
I was like god dammit he's right yes
call me up ladies called
he's like literally being like dude dog
wasting away this is no way he knows cuz
he'd been there he sees Delta you know
you can relate to it right so like that
whole death man was like but you know I
also I use it to inspire me at the same
time you know what I mean
and I try to like I don't know I guess
make music that would hopefully impact
people and you know in a similar way
away right I mean like I'm still gonna
do my fun stuff like tornado and escape
the last two songs because but those
aren't the ones those are the ones that
become your most streamed for obvious
reasons but they're not the ones that
mean the most right and I think that
pulls me into the song that I recorded
the day that I left the hospital I left
the hospital I had I had written the
song prediabetes but the whole diabetes
thing like just made it just even more
how much did the words did the words
change because sometimes I feel like
songs are written and you're like I
don't what the [__] that about and
then you read it two months later you're
like oh that's what that's none of them
changed they just [__] it was like I
wrote them not knowing that it was gonna
be more impactful so basically I was I
was producing to be for somebody else
and you know when you're like when
you're producing with Arcade you spend a
lot of time just going through sounds
and [__] right it's almost too exciting
to be honest right and so I found I
found like this sound and like this this
song will actually by the time this airs
by the time that this airs this song
will be out and it is called this is for
so for those that are listening it's
called this is for you may have already
heard it by now but just like this song
right here
ready
right and ice like I stumbled upon that
and immediately I just knew I was like
that I need to leave this other session
yeah start a new song right now because
I cannot lose that I can't forget that
yeah so I've made it I laid down that
angelic vocals and then I was like okay
just keep the drums simple so I just
drummed out like some cymbals I do and
then lightning Ferb I just use like
quarter note hats I didn't want anything
like so it's just like it is a rides
right and then I just made simp I played
simple chords on the piano I think it's
G minor a minor I think it's actually a
minor doesn't matter but I like did just
like some simple chords and I was like
that's it good it's all needs and then I
ended up writing the whole song that
same night that I made it and the song
is called this is for and I forget the
term there's that there's actual term
for this style of writing I don't
remember what it's called but it's when
everything almost everything starts with
the same line so like the song all it's
like three verses no hook
I got a poetic boner right now tonight
so it's like it's like a this is for
everything that I've invested this is
for working up being respected this is
for chance it's taking a fail pick
myself up and look at what I'm left with
this for the nights I was drinking too
much this isn't a nice number remember
very much this for the pain again in the
game and pushing for people the strength
of my name this for the drama this for
the doubt this for the skits and the
schemes in the cloud this for the doors
are dyed to break them win this for the
ones that could shut me up
and this for the show's with nobody
showing up this for the vision that's
threatening and closing up this for the
ones that still hope and I quit they
hope and I failing they hope and I slit
this for the friends that I've me in the
rear thought I lost control of the wheel
and can't steer but it's 2020 and I am
still here
this is for going to war with my fears
yes first one okay I can keep going
okay hey hey I'm ready I'm only sitting
while we're at it with the second one oh
my god how's the second one start uh if
I get the first line I'll be good I
think people are arguing that this song
will jet this song song by the time this
cool
March 1st in the sound Spotify app music
where all of its it'll be on all of it
so okay so second verse theme and this
is so now you can see now you can see
what I meant by the writing style Fergie
I wish I remembered but so then it's
like this is for all the nice I could
sleep this for the fact they obsess over
dreams this is for nights I thought I
lacked talent to make it despite having
all of the passion in this for the
studio back at my mom's dick in the go
or I roll my four songs this for the
scribbles and scratches and tears the
trashcan is full but that kept pushing
on this for the free styles were thought
of the squat sit still and liquor
written in the bong think oh we had it
even though we was broke by so many days
now this is all that we know and this
for the summers and all of the women I
used to make verses and playing the
victim and this for the ignorance needed
to grow so this is for me again hi all
alone and this for the drugs that I did
in the past thinking that those types of
habits class this for the Benner's that
brought in the bars it brought in the
fights and it brought in the scars this
for the sanity not thinking clear and
driving when I could not even steer but
it's 20/20 and I am still here this is
for going to war with my fish pursue
yeah love it there's one more you want
it yeah hit me without any day I need it
just keep going alright so this for the
team supporting the dream this is for
working that change in the scene this is
for half life and all of the fans they
play in our music they've reason their
hands this is for making some scrap
before wraps and then turn it around
just to give it all back and this for
the moment on Channel eight news just
because of the benefit concerts we do
this for the fortitude we had to show
just to get the throw in the greatest
shows just goes to show that Grandin
will get you to motor on stage where all
the lights close so this for the tears
enough every glass Rose past the
obstacles back in their past this for
the goosebumps this for the tears this
for adjustments we made every year this
for the trends to tie up loose ends for
not breaking when they all thought we
would Bend this for the blood this for
the sweat when adversity thought we
income and correct and this for the
armor we strapped on ourselves just to
get back to battle we taken the belt
this for the championship we've been
working for this for the fact that
nobody has earned it more this for my
mom this with my dad when I told him I
was gonna live off a rap for I knew we'd
be much bigger than that thank you for
showing you now how my back and this for
the patient shown by my sister this is
for every time I mister picture this for
the times I wasn't around cuz I was a
fight in the world
crowd this for my girl patellar but
neither could see my best friend of my
biggest believe the reason I'm alive is
to work in the sword for showing me
light what I'm stuck in the dark
brushing me off keep my mind clear so I
could keep finding the right path to
steer that's 2020 and we all are here
this is for me
conquering fears love it that I wrote
that that night and then like two weeks
later got diagnosed with diabetes almost
dad left the hospital that day we
recorded that song and knocked it out of
the park a lot better than the lyrics
didn't know I did I feel like it's kind
of dope occupy like you should open up
if I can open up shows with that like
don't even sing it just [__] - say it
- I'm just speaking like just what I did
just now that I spoke words that loved
it and then now that music video is
gonna drop - and it's gonna be the most
important thing that I've ever made
who would you be without writing who
would you if you weren't able to get
these things that are clearly inside of
you out to somewhere whether whether
people are listening to them not yeah
like if you if like if I put you in Ryan
Reid's hell and I gave you no notebooks
I gave you no voice to get this out who
would you be you think you'd be half the
man you are today without the ability to
get this art if you want express
yourself in this way special forces
murderer
I would kill people like like I know
that that sounds really dumb no I I
think that it doesn't what when I'm
trying to push out is I think that
there's a lot of us who call us creators
call us artists call us different left
brain thinkers right brain thinking
about [__] as I I think that a lot of
the times people think that that what a
creator does is for attention they think
that what a creator does is for
themselves but sometimes it's like this
is this is because I have to like it's
this thing that like I understand that
not everybody has it there's a thing
inside of me that if I don't have a
conversation with it or let it let it
have a conversation with the rest of the
world it's gonna eat me alive so I think
it's something that like is a genuine
calling that will just fester in us if
we don't get out no another thing I'd be
it's con dark I think I'd be a drunk
yeah yep I think I would I think without
music - - without art
to figure out who I am and be able to
you know like get all of this craziness
out into something that even if you know
even if not everybody hears it I at
least was able to give it life whether
that's through the keys or through the
drum pads you know whether it's through
the piano or the vocals like I was able
to breathe through arts I think I would
probably implode I think I would self
empty out and I think I would just
spiral into a lot of vice damn it me too
yeah I don't know if I'd be a good for
sure that you know we just sat out hope
that it's Oh be a good person because I
feel like I have a decent heart yeah but
I know so I don't know it's hard to
contend with me on this it's hard to
it's a lot to deal with like it's a lot
to like put into words but it's even
harder when you can't put it into words
when it's like the wind those words that
like you'd like that you just spoke that
are on your phone that are on papers
that are on that are in songs already
those words are in you you know a lot of
times and sometimes they're just taking
up a room it's like I don't know how to
understand this thing but getting it out
so I I just I always want to like put a
hole in it put a peg in it because I
think that even people who even if
you're not trying to be on a stage even
if you're not trying to be a rapper
musician and producer if you are able to
get lyrics out if you can write songs if
you just sing by yourself if you get any
words on paper even if it's just
journaling to yourself it's so healing I
think that that so many humans can
benefit from just [__] writing and
getting out the words that they don't
know are inside of them agreed you know
I mean you don't gotta show anybody ever
yeah I don't have to do it for yourself
yep yeah I am with that I have a quick
question do you do you by chance have
like juice or anything sugar yes I
definitely do let me go grab okay I can
tell that my blood Sugar's low which is
another funny thing as you start to
really start to read your body yeah
that's good that you would read your
body let me go run and grab that real
quick if you want to entertain you talk
about entertain the people all right
here's what you need to talk about you
need to talk about you
gameplan and keep in mind that your girl
was right down the road so you gotta
handle that while I'm upstairs here's
the Sarat scenario I'm getting you some
juice and you just see a [__] zombie
hand punch through that window okay that
means I have a limited time to look
around at my surroundings I need to
figure out what's around me so we have
the good thing is that we're in a
basement that has been turned into a
music studio so there's a lot of metal
there's a lot of heavy things I have a
microphone stand which is it one of the
round based ones it is one of the round
based ones oh man
for those of y'all that don't know the
the round bases are usually the concrete
of like the so obviously so that the mic
stand stays upright so if I flip that
upside down take the top off I got like
a three-foot basically like hammer like
war hammer of concrete so I'm probably
gonna use that to see the one that
breaks its hand through the wall or
through the window I come running at it
I smash that [__] and just beat
the [__] out of him
hopefully and then I obviously check out
that window to see how many more we got
okay next Karissa who brought me here
she's about like well luckily she's only
like three three blocks down so that's
not too terrible I can make that happen
and so I'm gonna call her after I beat
the [__] out of that first zombie and oh
thank you so much you brought me all the
things okay okay where we have these
zombies as you're pouring this alright
so basically what I did was I your mic
stand I was telling the people that
those the the round based mic stands
usually have the accrete bottoms yeah
they're heavy so I'm gonna take the top
out of that I'm gonna use that as like a
warhammer to at least kill the one
that's jumping through the window or
trying to jump through the window then I
got a survey the scene I got to see how
many are in your yard yeah yeah and then
I got a call Karissa and be like yo are
you dead yet right are you still alive
should I do I need to come
you you because if you already did then
bummer it's every man for himself like
I'm not gonna waste my time forehead so
like I'm just saying if you don't answer
right it's a done deal
so she answers and she's like yeah but
they're they're like coming in from in
crouching us from all angles she's still
at that coffee shop I'm like all right
see if you can like barricade yourself
with bookshelves cuz that's also a
library right right right
there's coffee things there so there's
gotta be something that's like metal and
heavy not let's try to arm yourself with
some even if it's a lamp all right I'll
be there probably not like a paper book
maybe like a hardcover book ideally
right and then um so then I'm like I bro
you have a decision to make I gotta go
get Carissa I go with you okay so no
down with me all right so the good no
stutter I got it perfect I appreciate
you for that
honorable respect so we have like
luckily the door is right there so as
long as they haven't gotten into the
house and whatnot we can skedaddle out
of here pretty easily worst-case
scenario we could fit through that
window you have weight sets in your
garage so we're gonna need to go I gotta
work out real quick no we need heavy
things okay okay um so we can arm
ourselves with some dumbbells and then
or even like the the the bench bar the
bench press bar right scoops 45 man do
just get and get spinning in a circle
and that thing my backyard you could
take out 25 - sighs I don't know if you
have guns uh no I'm just getting it like
I have some like secret gun thing I'm
just [__] bird from Trevor's next door
know what you ask everybody there zombie
questions so I'm not gonna be surprised
if you hit a button and run just kinda
prepare nexor just like flips upwards
and then it's just like maybe it is
I don't know what I would do though like
I dude it's so crazy to think about like
you you think that you could handle it
but I think when even came down to like
the act of any of us humans actually
like trying to hit like even though it's
a zombie who's trying to kill you can be
so hard to make your brain and actually
like kill like smash a head i'd--
another like person thing I think when
you I think humans when they're backed
up against the wall you know capable
instincts come out and I think that
adrenaline would allow you to smash the
[__] out of zombie right Elyse doesn't
girls I'm dead if I don't you know it's
do or die it's killer be killed but then
the next question is so so here's the
hard part about the zombie thing right
the zombie thing sucks because I would
rather fast forward like six months into
the zombie apocalypse and live then
right okay because it's the first if you
survive the initial chaos you your
chances skyrocket a super true because
then you're fighting people almost like
I know how to fight zombies I'll kill
him real quick but then it's just like
other [__] right and then so
what do you need you need food actually
I'm screwed yeah you just realized your
son oh my god I never even thought about
the insulin thing so I have to not only
raid a grocery store but I got to make
sure that that grocery store has a
pharmacy mmm-hmm and I need to raid all
of their insulin right and then I need
to figure out how I could survive like
like I'd have to figure out how to make
[__] insulin like you just see we'd
have to get like a bunker situation and
we'd have to start like a quick little
month-long science thing where we just
like we'll just somehow learn how to
synthesize whatever you have for your
blood sugar I need to start that now
yeah well I mean they did it on I am
Legend like Will Smith seemed to be able
to figure out the whole lab thing so we
should be able to see the situation he
was in it starts in the the good part it
starts in the okay and like he's already
got I mean it starts with him already
having a habit he's already got really
[__] trained canine companion like
you know he's yeah it's true I worry
about the initial chaos of getting what
you need to bunker down when everybody's
freaking out the military is freaking
out people are getting killed not only
by zombies but other humans desperation
kicks absolutely once you make it past
that first wave and you figured out how
to have a semi-regular food supply and
ideally ammunition and guns yeah you get
a lot better chance
I feel like there'd be so many like in a
town like this there's so many
[__] with guns who just love
shooting their guns like anyway just des
monts whatever I feel like what if what
if like we're all concerned about it
it's like ya know Castle Rock Washington
is completely fine because they've been
defending their own yeah
like just set up barricade we just have
a bunch of [__] like on their
houses and recliners just shooting
zombies with shotguns I could picture it
I had a to your father I think maybe
he's retired mr. Clausen he was a
history teacher
yeah so he was a he was just just
baller-ass teacher I just I loved him
but I always pictured like if there's a
zombie apocalypse I feel like I'd
probably make my way to his house cuz he
would be on the roof just Cap'n zombies
like he would show us like history
movies and then he would just like stop
it like he would [__] like he would show
us like the war scene from Coral Harbor
but then like the other stuff started
and he just stopped the movie man I
can't all [__] lies look he was just
like he would be like not let us deal
with the [__] just tell us the truth
so but then here's the thing is that it
depends what type is Ami's you know
that's all it depends on you know other
words these zombies were toasty we're
toasted world I never saw a movie was
that the really fast one with Brad Pitt
yeah do they suppress that a sacrifice I
can I've to they were kinda like ants
like they'll like like sacrifice
themselves like stack each other on each
other to get over this wall see that's
like that's scary yeah done it's the
like shoot what was that popular show
forever walking dead all right if it's
like those zombies I feel a lot more
safe with that yeah they're slower like
the um the ones from I am Legend mm-hmm
yeah like superhuman started to get
smarter and smarter right that can think
yeah okay then we got some other
questions and also honestly I haven't
even I don't even have like enough
canned food
you know what I mean yeah I have like a
chicken yeah I wouldn't last very long I
would definitely have to like get some
supplies that's for sure and then you
got to be willing if it came down to it
if it came down between like your camp
like you and your loved ones versus
somebody else in their loved ones right
you got to be willing to do what you
have to do to survive the humanity is
going to lose ya know like you're gonna
it's gonna the people that the the
heartless [__] that already
have like the crazy Doomsday Preppers
they're like yeah who's [__] laugh and
now you don't I mean they're gonna be so
confident oh man they're so stoked to
you know what they're actually they're
so stoked because they're like like yeah
I am your God now
like y'all are clamoring to me I didn't
I meet you denied me for Seoul all right
I feel like that's kind of how some of
our politicians get in some ways but hey
all the other conversation give me a
let's let's let's roundabout on here
we'll give you another you know 15 20
whatever you're comfortable with let's
go with ya I mean I'm down to go until
you're like right this is way too long
well I want it I mean it's not too long
for me I I definitely do want to make
sure I cover some Soho I mean I think
I'm at like in total I was like we can
go yeah oh yeah yeah no no I just wanted
to make sure we hit a couple things and
then let it go from there and tell me
about half life okay I feel like because
you know I want to hear it from like the
the I want to inspire people who are
like you're all back up a bit I always
had this like [__] it I'll do it myself
thing like it like I wrote it's like a
rust rust thing that I grab onto but
even before before Russ is mentality
that I loved there's always this like
like if nobody's gonna put me on a put
myself on like when I when I first
started throwing shows when I first
started DJing like I like I didn't know
what to do I just thought music was cool
and I thought electronic music was cool
there was nowhere to play it and so I
just start throwing my own shows put
myself on build my own thing and I want
to like inspire anybody who is maybe has
an idea and I kind of wonder if I could
do it but like nobody in their life
tells them that they should do it
because it's like you know it is hard
work and it does start small but it does
grow and it grows into these different
things so I don't know keep in mind that
that I think you're super [__]
inspiring and I think whatever whatever
you tell do whatever your truth is is
going to be inspiring for anybody who's
starting the journey so tell me what
halfway right okay so half life is
something that started as a belief
system that always had the similar core
but it has like grown and evolved
multiple times so if you throw it all
the way all the way back it's a joke
half was like this joke that started
with me and my cross country buddies and
it did not stand for whole permission
fortitude it started first the four
hardest [__] and it was super sarcastic
like we this was the time when like the
word Yolo was like a very normal popular
thing like it was right and we always
did it as like a like a parody of Yolo
it was like all bro hard is [__] I
wouldn't actually you know like we
painted that we're like hard as [__]
right yeah but so it started that right
and then the reason that it's stuck
around and and what a lot of people you
know probably understand is the reason I
stuck around is because that was my
initial core support system like we so
it went this was back and and and then
another another thing is that it started
as half clan which obviously we changed
for obvious reasons because effect the
word clan was not like a you wouldn't
even faze yourself with that word back
then we were gamers oh well that's what
you do you clan up yeah on night either
xbox or ps3 we all play Call of Duty
right and so half clan was our clan like
that on Call of Duty it had nothing to
do with you know any sorta isn't it piss
you off that like stupid groups take
away an entire word well here's a deal
if I would have been open my if I would
have like looked at the the the US and
as a whole and looked at my and and you
know like thought about my future more I
would have been like this is probably
not something that we want to enter
music let alone hip-hop with you don't
have it right right I get that my scope
wasn't that big right you know like this
is so so it started this in cross
country and then we all hung out like
every weekends and we gamed
you know and it was like half clan was
our was our gamertag right and that's
what that so then when I started like
first doing music and I started like
first doing shows guess who like we came
we squad my very first show and I
remember cuz it pissed off all like the
older artists and [__] cuz I'm like 18
at the time I'm young as [__] and like
there was like nobody really at the show
it was that loss trochus and I showed up
like 30 people deep just like a bunch of
kids right and it was a lot of them were
the the cross country kids
my gamer dudes and wrestlers do you want
I mean you some bros yeah and so like we
squat out 30 deep and then they they all
ended up we went first they made me go
first cuz like the new kid nobody knows
me so we're all raging for my [__] and
then and then after I'm done performing
they all leave mm-hmm and then all the
others like well people get worried yeah
dude it's I didn't even understand the
scene back then so like it just
naturally transitioned into my core
families so yeah he's stuck and then I
wanted it to mean something more and so
that's when the acronym came and this
was like this was about the time that's
um you know I had max already explained
this in his interview but you know I
asked him to come and hype man and then
we started making music together and
then he just like we just became Bros on
it like you know we it became an us
thing pretty quickly right like even
though I started it he became apart
pretty early on and has been obviously
you know a huge part of it and that was
about when we wanted we thought we
wanted to take it more seriously and so
I decided to change it to hope and
mission forward to because I want it to
be something I wanted to stay with half
because of the roots you know and I
didn't want to leave those but I wanted
it to mean something because we always
wanted to be we still wanted to be
empowering so that's our half-life came
out or have claim at the time and then
you know max took you a whole through
the whole thing of bringing on Yanis
later on and and then you know just
recently we brought on three other
artists but the whole thing about
half-life was self-sufficiency and DIY
like we I knew we were not gonna be
accepted by the industry I mean we were
hardly even accepted by our own City you
know let alone other town states you
know like in the whole industry I knew
that we were going we were not gonna be
accepted by everybody so that's when
that natural DIY energy started to take
over and we started doing everything
that we could by ourselves from the jump
yeah and so we started throwing more
shows you know I got and and you know
like the first show I got handed to me
and then
cat caught fever after that and I
started just like trying to figure out
who the the promoters were who was the
movers and shakers name in there so long
view
right so like not really much at all
but I still had to work with what I had
and then so then we just started doing
all these shows and we were trying we're
trying we're trying to knit was like
y'all corny corny corny oh don't matter
like you're not gonna make it and then
Anna and I we just I just kept lon and
it's kept pushing and like it was if you
had to boil down the DIY part of it it's
absolutely lack of acceptance you know
what I mean like that you'll do right
and so it's like you know like you said
wolf nobody's gonna do it for me I'm
gonna do for myself
and that's why nowadays with like you
know we put our own shows together you
know I go I go right to the venue and I
don't even deal with the Booker half the
time I'll go right to the venue and be
like who's in charge who don't need to
talk to I need to get a date and then we
get it down and then I talked to the
charities about you know throwing it in
their name and their man or you don't I
mean like I put the the lineup together
and and we handle everything as an
in-house unit right and that's because
like you know it went from getting [__]
on to finally started getting accepted
and then people tried to start taking
advantage of us and like you know
basically trying to like get a little
you know her off of [__] that I worked
for them that we worked for that we
built you know and so that's not gonna
[__] fly and so like I and also I
just got tired of the way the scene does
things like it's so selfish it's so
crabs in a bucket everybody would just
be so willing to throw down their fellow
man to raise himself up a little bit
when really like what what like like oh
we're all battling for the scene what
[__] scene yeah what scene it like and
so I just got tired of the egos I got
tired of like walk Portland's this
Portland's that what the okay says who
yeah right who's the brain who if you
become McLemore and blow up who granted
who was also a cornball I respect what
he did I do I respect what he did but
musically not my favorite but I
respect you know that he like came up
where nobody really did he did his own
thing many exactly so like that I
respect it like the way he moved I
respected I was like if you do that in
Portland you can start trying to make
some calls about Portland you know
there's obviously some there's some
people that some of some older heads
that have been in the province in
forever
and I don't even try and like you know
look that's yeah absolutely y'all but
that's the thing is is I think that's
the thing that you did though is it's
not about we think there's gatekeepers
and we're like okay well I'm doing this
music so I got to go who are the hip-hop
God so I have to ask permission to play
hip-hop in their town in do I gotta suck
you know it's no it's like hey I want to
do something that's it so it's it's own
thing it's just for us it's a thing that
we do and I'm gonna do it this way and
I'm gonna and you could cut out the
middleman I think so many people think
that there's a gatekeeper magic like
like oh I got to go to this guy who
knows this guy so I don't disrespect
this and I mean I there there is a thing
about culture and you know like not
stepping on culture but I also think
that that [__] can be so [__] boxing
in and stupid so let me give let me get
something said like alright just because
I want to do things my own way does not
mean that I do not respect the culture
right the culture of music the culture
of hip-hop the culture of Portland right
I'm just not going to try to pretend
like I'm an advocate for the culture
because that's not my place excellent
I can still build my company and be
successful and hopefully give to the
culture because I respect like you know
I'm trying to get I'm trying to get rid
of the stigma that is like so selfish
right so like I respect the culture but
a lot of these other people who are are
way more like justified to represent the
culture I just feel like they aren't
doing their best representation like you
know and there's there's some that are
but then there's others that aren't
because of the ego and the the
selfishness and the crabs in a bucket
mentality so me wanting to do things my
own way is it ignoring the culture or
thinking that I can represent it better
it's not my place
not my [__] job but I love to make
music I love to put on shows I love to
give back to the community I love
I love what I do and I respect what I do
and that's why I'm not gonna take no for
an answer
Yeah right like you could be like you
don't belong here that's okay
Yeah right exactly like I love what I do
I love art I love music and I love to be
able to give people amazing
entertainments and then when I can give
it back it's why we did the Doernbecher
show the YWCA show that's why we did the
toy drive
mm-hm you know where's more of that you
know right not trying to be a dick but
like nobody who else is doing that
right you know what I mean so that's
everybody's looking out for number one
man you know community is something I
always like to expand on the word
community on this podcast what's your
what's your view on community I mean
obviously you you create your own
community that's for sure and that's
prevalent but there also is like you
trickle into other communities akyuu my
talk about like like trappers persona
purse trauma for example he does a back
flip back and back way back when and
then all set numbers ago we can do back
flips and then two big sighted people
are doing back flips so like I think you
even in your own community like with
with your half life that's your
community you know and obviously it's
expanding farther and farther and it has
its reach its its arms its veins but
just by you loving your own community
and you guys all like believing each
other within yours even just like going
anywhere near other communities it
inspires them and it pushes them to me
expand on community for me what's right
so if if you from an outside perspective
see and feel that then I am I am doing
my job like one thing that we talk a lot
about you know because Rula Delgado is a
very inspiring artist very inspiring
human and the things that he's done for
his Portland scene especially in the
lgbtqia+ I think I got them all you know
basically the the the scene of like
people who are struggling with
self-identity right and that the
inspiring things that he's been able to
do with people who struggle with their
identity you know because he's he's a
big overweight black gay rapper and he's
like but guess what
not only can I love Who I am you can
love who you are too oh yeah and it's
incredible I mean
strapped a pride flag around that dudes
neck so that he could wear it on Moda
center stage with no shirt on and do a
song about getting blackballed by his
community when he came out of the closet
yeah yeah a rapper right
and so like we talk about this all the
time because I am I get inspired by that
[__] every day for his
willingness to be who he is be honest
with himself right and inspire other
people to be honest yeah I mean him
talking about all the time with a
strong-ass place that he stands man
right it's incredible and he has the
power to really and that's one of the
reasons that you know I I really wanted
him to be a part of half-life is because
he's exactly what we're working towards
and what we're striving for and so we
talk about all the time he's like dude I
he's like I feel like he's like I feel
like I finally found family like he's he
can tell you his own upbringing story
he'd be a great guest to have on what
have a month yeah but he has his own
story that you know I not my place to
talk about but he's like I finally like
I feel like I have a family and I fit in
and so we just want that to resonate and
we want that to spread you know what I
mean and so for you to like I said from
an outside perspective feel like you're
already starting to see that then I'm
doing my job right you don't mean like I
want I like I want you to wake up and
feel a little more empowered than you
did yesterday you know what I mean like
I want you I want you to win the fight
you know do I want everybody to win
their fight one if you can do that by
filling your cup right right that you
feel it filling your cup so much that it
overflows right not not not in the
traditional cup runneth over sense yeah
yeah not like a like let's just see how
I can fill my cup just for me and keep
it to myself it's like you you fill your
cup like you focus on what's good for
you you focus on your community and you
guys up you guys bring each other up
right you guys are fulfilling to each
other and then that overflows that's
exactly it and here's the thing man is
that like community I feel like is
something that gets really lost
misunderstood misconstrued and you know
it's really just like giving a [__]
about your fellow human you know what I
mean and wanting to see your other human
thrive
and we're in a weird place like society
wise politically you know no matter how
you feel about the current president you
can't some whether you like him or hate
him
you can't say that he hasn't increased
the divide between you know ideas and
and thoughts and beliefs and like all of
this division is is starting to resonate
in communities whereas now what aching
and what if you're in the clique what if
you and somebody else have always been
in the same community loved each other
support each other whatever and then all
of a sudden you find out that one of you
is a trump supporter and one of you is a
Bernie Sanders supporter mm-hmm how many
people like that are strong enough to
put personal political beliefs aside
yeah and and still want each other to
thrive right now that we're starting to
see dissolve like because of your
personal beliefs now you have to go on
the offensive and you can't want your
other fellow human to to thrive as much
right right which you know seems like oh
sorry shitty but that's what we do yeah
you know what I mean so like I don't
know I guess like where we're going into
like we're starting to move into a place
where it sees like all inclusive or all
exclusive you know and we're starting to
see that Venn diagram start to separate
yeah why I I ain't about that no I ain't
about I'm about connection I have front
from my left shoulder braid blade to my
right shoulder blade I have the words
humanity in the negative space
tattooed in and you know sometimes I
[__] and I literally like wonder what it
means to me like because it seemed like
the definition changes sometimes and I
think through all this [__] through all
the Trump through all the burning
through all the [__] you're 20 years
old you're 25 years old through all this
the one common thing we all have is
where none of us know [__] and we're all
humans you know I mean right like like
[__] man we got to be on each other's
side it's not it's humans against all of
our problems it's not all of us against
each other manners and so I think
community and expanding on what
community is and just like letting other
people you know you believe in it I know
and so if you look if you if you look at
it from like a historical standpoint
there has always been
war no matter what right
but technically we're a lot more
open-minded and aware than we were back
then like at least we're not at least
we're going in the direction over time
where we're killing each other less
because of your specific for instance
religious beliefs you know I mean we're
back then they would just decimate an
entire like civilization because one was
Catholic one was Christian you know or
we've definitely grown right so then
it's like so as we get into the most
aware I was talking to somebody else
talking us might lyft driver the other
day and he's like in his 70s and he's
like I'll tell you one thing like you
guys you're the generation cuz I've seen
like four generations and I was like
yeah that's crazy for you to say that
because usually they're just like you're
lazy and entitled he's like I've seen
four generations and there was not one
of those generations with a generation
before them didn't say you're lazy
entitled so he's like don't trip on that
too much they men say in that moment
he's like but you all the first ones to
come up with like to grow up with
unlimited resource and unlimited
knowledge because of cell phones
internet technology oh that's the writ
like it seriously say that again we we
have unlimited knowledge limb if you
have a question you don't have to ask
your aunt who knows everything about
rocking like if you have any question
about cooking the Internet has every
answer you need so the the point that he
made that was so important was that we
are less likely to be stuck to our
closed-minded beliefs of our immediate
families friends and ancestors which I
thought was huge it's like we're in the
biggest time where like you can have
whatever type of mind you want you could
stand by whatever you want to stand by
you're not just limited to like what my
parents believed or because if you look
at things like racism racism is like
very taught it's very you know what I
mean like more my parents and my
grandparents and my great-grandparents
you want a meme that was never
questioned right but now you can
question anything so like it's just
crazy to see this divide that's
happening between like love and hey
and where that's gonna go into the
future now that we are all more
connected than we've ever been and I
hope that it goes in the direction of
open-mindedness right but only time will
tell I think that as as artists and
people who you know people look up to
you and I in a certain way it's you know
at least a handful once in a while right
so I think by just like seeing that and
seeing it from an outside perspective
and being like well you know as much as
we talk about communities and in people
doing this and people doing that like we
are the people and we are the
communities right so you know listener
if you're it ever and any sort of
leadership role of any sorts if
somebody's looking up to you whether
it's a little kid whether it's your
neighbor whether it's you are the person
in your neighborhood who never ever
forgets to put your garbage out right
what you're doing man people are
watching be inspiring be be dude it's
the craziest [__] time in right now
what's happening in the world especially
the internet and all the political crap
is is there's little tornadoes it's like
hey it wherever there's a problem or
wherever there's a disagreement we now
have a magnifying glass from the
disagreement we've stirred up and we
give it a little tornado and we and all
the problems come up and what we're
doing is we're like we're fighting all
the problems we're punching out the
[__] debris and the air try and like
no no that's bad that's evil this is
evil no here's what I believe in but we
need to remember that like the dust is
gonna settle you know this [__] dust
is gonna settle and in in who you are
through all this crazy [__] in
America right now you know give give
yourself some grace and let yourself
change and let yourself grow let
yourself look at your actions and see
how they let yourself build your own
community how about that right now yeah
and understand that the example that you
set may or may not be followed by a
number of people that you don't even
realize you know like if you set an
actin a accidental bad example you know
thinking I will you know that's not
gonna resonate that's that he you know
was what was that that like the
butterfly effect you know and the
raindrop you know you know you know like
you said you don't know how many people
are looking up to you and are inspired
by that and so like whatever type of
examples you're setting is gonna
resonate beyond what you think it is
especially with
social media and everybody on earth
seeing exactly what examples you're
setting yeah exactly
that's crazy thing about social media
that's a whole nother hugging I'm always
going off about social media it's such a
blessing and a curse I think the biggest
thing that I I just love saying on
social media really quick is like why do
you feel need to be connected all the
time right you see just saying just just
take a look at that like I like it you
know it's even cell phones even texting
if you think about it so something that
like in the last two years that like my
friends been super cool about
understanding is like yeah I'm gonna
text Jake and he's probably not gonna be
back till tomorrow right like I'm not
available
like in in my life and my mental health
is better for it and I think that a lot
of people who are very very very
addicted to social media like I was I
was crazy to Cru social media just just
take a look if it's [__] pulling you
in a little too much and know that it's
okay to take a break completely texting
all this you can take a break from your
phone right so the unfortunate thing is
when you have a business but no I was
gonna say it's gonna get worse because
like you know this is and a lot of
people been saying this you know sound
off I'm just being a betta or beating it
will go the dead horse cuz I don't know
if I'm being a dead horse here but like
when people go through middle school
they are so impressionable and and and
that's when they mentally build like
validation and what validation means to
them and what validation means to
society
absolutely so we're actually the last of
the generation that are like like me and
you are old enough to where we didn't
have to go through social media
validation in like middle school right
now these people are going through
middle school with like Instagram and
Facebook oh my gosh likes Iife it makes
me like a sad and nervous for like right
so we're not teaching the right
validation habits and it's just it's
making you know so then all the sudden
you know you like your slave to that
phone because that phone
you're valid your sense of self-worth
and your sense of validation is now that
phone meaning you are that like you are
slave to that phone because without that
you don't feel so you don't feel
validated don't feel like you're with
you feeling comfortable you don't like
you don't like sitting in a room where
you like I'm not touching my phone like
that feeling that you get where you have
to grab your phone that's what that is
you're avoiding feeling there right and
you know what and that's something that
like so you know you said that I inspire
you but like you really got to
understand how much that you inspire me
and a lot of that is because you've
really like taking your own mental state
into your own hands and you've you know
you like your your process your your
journey of disconnecting so that you can
refine Jake Ryan's or find Jake grounds
for the first time if that's the case
you know I mean that is so strong and
powerful because like most people don't
have the strength to even think about
what they might be like in their own
strength in their own mind state right
and like I come into here and and you
have all of this riding on the walls and
you have all of these sticky notes
everywhere everywhere of just your
thoughts and ideas and you're willing to
sit with your ideas and not feel like
you have to run away to either an escape
on your phone or run away to validation
from others on your phone for you to
start to feel okay and that process dude
is like you're one of the greatest
humans that I know and like I've missed
yeah super honored to to be your friend
for that reason because that is so
strong like which shouldn't that
shouldn't be a thing yeah right you
shouldn't have to think that like oh he
doesn't use his his phone he doesn't use
the phone all the time like what a
strong human
yeah well bird it dude it to it said
thanks so much for saying that I really
I really appreciate that
because you're very inspiring to me as a
friend but I think that like it's
something new as humans man like it's
something that like you got to kind of
look at where we're at in 2020 and you
know 2007 when iPhone was invented to
2020 13 years man look at human beings
take yourself out of the equation and
look at us on a timeline in a history
book and think about like what are they
going to be typing up about like how are
the humans affected by the cell phones
like
bro you gotta take a look at that and
realizing you're one of them you're one
of them right now in a we record but uh
but do it and one thing I was one
emphasize is like I and I in this is
part of me I'm trying to get good at
taking compliments because sometimes I
finally it's dissociate and reject it
and so no but but I want to emphasize
that like I'm not a perfect man
I've had many mistakes I've had many
flaws I probably have more flaws you
know or a but probably make more
mistakes but I am able to what happened
to social media thing is I was able to
like take a look at the mistakes look at
the ways that I was doing that the the
ways that I was thinking in realizing
like this isn't gonna last for me this
is stupid
this is this is not in my benefit and
just taking and honestly like the
typical part of like you know they say
addiction is like admitting that you
have a problem and it sounds corny and
when we've heard that a million times
but like dude with cell phones and like
validation of other people like I
definitely had a problem like I had a
problem with with seeking validation and
people looking up to me and making sure
I was popular and also making sure that
I kept this like everybody thinks I'm a
nice guy like I don't want to cry in
front of people because then they're
gonna think that I'm just lying and like
opening up to see that you are this way
and say like it's not really benefiting
me though right and then being able to
go from there and say what can I take
off like what armor can I start to
remove and mic [__] dude for me it start
moving scales and skin and more and more
you know I break it I believe in but
you're like it's gonna but it's so worth
it I just think like you know I I want
to do good and I want to be a good man I
haven't always been perfect and I'm not
gonna be perfect but I want it yeah but
but yeah and I think just like realizing
that that we're all like that like we're
all like like I'm a man I've been a boy
I have boy tendencies like you're a man
you've been a boy yeah boy tendencies
like same thing with females like any of
us just just know that your life is
worth worth it to just say you know what
I'm gonna start over I'm gonna I'm gonna
rethink my thoughts they're not [__]
helping me out just be willing to like
lose the attention for a while lose the
attention from social media lose the the
momentum that you
like I like you know I lost a lot of
gigs just DJing like because I wasn't
responding to my Facebook post I wasn't
responding my Instagram cuz I deleted
that [__] but it's like so I lost out on
those but my life grew in so many other
ways I think we got to be willing to
sacrifice a lot of what we have to to
build what we what we know we can be and
have love faith in ourselves and but
that balance also is so hard because of
the fact that businesses have rebranded
the way they work to revolve around
social media as well mm-hmm
you know it means that's the only thing
about like having a you know being being
a DJ comes with a same with you know
what I'm doing is that it's it's almost
a necessary part when businesses are
going out of business because they
refuse to adapt to social media
yeah that's everywhere that's dude like
it like it's like it when I go to eat
somewhere like if I go look and see if
their hours are open or what their menu
is and like if they're online doesn't
like match up or they don't have like a
menu I'm gonna be at well next right
like exactly this is how the world works
exactly so but there is a huge balance
like not letting it suck you in like
like me saying like well I have a DJ
business I have to stay online it's not
an excuse for me to check my phone every
six minutes
you know exactly like don't do email bro
I think and I think that anybody who
wants to cut down their social media use
I know that's not exactly what we're
talking about but just in that specific
subject just give yourself like set the
timers or just say like I don't do
notifications and I don't check it
randomly like I check it every day at 8
p.m. or I check it every day at 5 p.m. I
let myself have a half hour and then I
do not check that [__] until 5
p.m. the next day or whatever it is set
some limits for yourself I think and
then also just just I guess just
inspiring people to be the best versions
of themselves so I think just realizing
that that wherever you're at you're not
your thoughts you know like we have
those Wolf's we you know sometimes
sometimes all our thoughts are the bad
wolf man like they're just they're just
just cravings and desires and in
[__] you know and realizing that
like having faith that you can start to
fill your brain with in your body in
your life with those good thoughts even
when they're not there
thinking that just I want to give any
listener like I'm proof of that like I
had no good thoughts like I hated myself
I wanted to die that's what I thought
about but but I sat down here and I just
looked at the wall with a pen in my hand
I was like [__] dude
what do I think what's going like why do
I think like this what's happening here
I started riding at dude and I started
just I don't know I mean I just want to
I want to make sure everybody knows like
if you're in the [__] darkest pits
here's a good one Ryan tell me think of
back to one of your most dark moments
growing up as an artist as a man as a
teenager as a mid-20s think what would
if you could reach back in time was a
[__] portal that opens up in time to
when you were 20 or 16 or whatever right
and it grabs you by the shirt collar and
it's you from the future and it says
listen here [__] here's what you
need to hear what would you tell him oh
man was they need to hear what did you
need to hear at any point in your life
probably stop trying so hard to be
something or not which I know that's
also kind of cliche but like really like
if I if I could get back all the years
of me trying so hard to be this persona
that I wasn't to be and because I'm
still suffering from that I know that
there's a lot of people that have a
negative view of Who I am because of the
way that I used to act and a lot of
years that I've spent pretending out
somebody that I wasn't and like I'll
have people I'll have people now even
like you know people that I knew from
like way back and the bag I mean like
yeah you used to be such a douche bag
and I'm like that's fair but what you
know but I haven't I guess I haven't
done enough job and this probably
because I don't you know spend too much
time on social media like being personal
personal there's still a lot of people
that think
still that person and I feel like I've
got a small-town thing for sure right
and if I put a lot of effort into just
becoming a good human you know and I
don't say that like like I'm such a good
dude you know what I mean I mean like
I've really tried to be a good human and
like care and and and be there for
people that are in my life that need it
and like I've just really tried to just
be I don't even know how to put it with
I was just a good human and I feel like
a lot of decisions and and and ways that
I acted in the past now even overshadow
that still to this day you know so if I
didn't spend so much time just like cuz
at the time I didn't know who I was and
so instead of taking the time to figure
out who I was and in coming to myself I
just like built this persona but it's
like ego centric [__] persona because
I was and part of that stems from the
fact that I was so just upset with
nobody like really believing to me and
like everybody clowning on me then I was
finally like I then [__] y'all you know
what I mean then if y'all come believe
in me then like you know it's it's me
first the world like you know [__]
everybody else and this and that and
then like that just made me just a dark
human and you know human that I'm not
proud of and and so that sucks that that
still a lot of people still have that
that image of me yeah I think that I
think that like a lot of times people
have opinions of each other or holding
on to opinions of each other like that
they don't even realize like they'll be
like like a lot of people wouldn't
realize like so if somebody saw you and
they hadn't seen him for five years like
they're gonna see you and instantly
bring back to like like I know Ryan he's
19 and he's a cocky [__] right
but like what what doesn't happen but
but podcasts and things and
conversations like this allowed to
happen is we put a wedge in and we say
hey I know as that person just letting
you know if you give me a chance
I'm gonna show you that I'm not that
person right and that's a big open up
you know yeah like it so so if that
scenario happened where I walk you know
I saw somebody that I haven't seen in X
amount of years
a lot of times you end up not having
even like even like a 15-minute
conversation you'd be like wow he's I
feel like he's grown up a lot yeah I
love walking away from that like when
you see somebody you're like [__] that
do something good right well then but
then you don't even have that
conversation so instead of having that
15 minute like completely like paradigm
shifting conversation you don't have
that conversation and then they just
continue thinking you're that same dude
from five minutes or from five years ago
when we could have like a 15 minute
conversation and like re meet each other
for who we are now all right you know
like in the same vice-versa
you know I might have preconceived ideas
about that person right and so I could
like we could just you know hash it out
15 minutes and we bro I think giving
each other room to grow like it dude
it's it's always such a good reminder
for me of just like I don't know [__]
you don't know [__]
you didn't ask to be born do you
remember being asked to be born Ryan
Reid right but I didn't I don't remember
being at like dude I'm here and I'm
going through my [__] and I'm sorry that
I'm not perfect but like I'm gonna try
to get better and in like dude there's
nobody walking around saying they have
everything figured out
there's nobody walking around outside
saying I am I am perfect we look at each
other and were like oh they think
they're so perfect like did they say
that to you
did they [__] say that they like I
think just remembering like we're all on
our growth period and we're all like
every conversation every re meeting
every every like every new day is a new
day you know I mean like you can restart
and you can give someone else the
benefit out you can give them room to
change and sometimes that's that's a lot
of you know I I I really believe in just
believing in your homies and believing
in even strangers and I think sometimes
just believing in someone and letting
them have room to grow and breathe I
think is enough to like like allow them
to be back all right well I'm gonna I'm
gonna take it in my own hands and
actually do what they think do it if
more people had that mentality we can
spread it we would thrive so that's and
you know and that that's that's one of
the reasons that this podcast is so dope
is that it like gives people not only a
platform to tell their story and and and
hopefully inspire some people around
them
then the people listening they might be
inspired by the fact that they're so
open in growth and changed that then
they decide to grow and change and then
butterfly butterfly effect their closest
homie exactly like man like so you
putting yourself on a platform to be
able to try to start that ripple effect
of just positive growth is just that's
[__] amazing right hey man is it
sounds like everybody in their mother
does podcasts these days and so the fact
that yours is like yeah but it's for a
purpose right it's for a meeting you
know what's actually crazy about that
that brings me back to what we were
talking about the beginning about our
blinders right is like I honestly do it
doesn't even like it doesn't cross my
mind the other [__] have
podcasts like I like I listen to
podcasts that I enjoy you know but I'm
never like looking at people who are
kind of doing what I'm doing like
thinking like oh they're already doing
that I can't do that like what I'm just
I'm literally doing what I believe in
right I'm just I'm just I'm like oh I
know I know cool people I know a
fuckload of cool people right and
somehow like those cool people allow me
to meet new cool people right and I can
just talk to him and we'd have cool
people conversation it's just yeah but I
do it's a talk about like the Microsoft
versus the Microsoft versus Apple like
Microsoft's they're looking at like how
do we beat Apple like what's Apple doing
we gotta make you one
I actually I think we should because I
have to pee too okay um and I'm sweating
a little bit you want to just you want
to send off the folks oh yeah how deep
are we we're pretty deep it's been deep
that's always my fear is that we're
around two hours oh okay yeah we get I
mean you should finish your Microsoft
Apple thing that yeah and then we'll
both piece so this would be the last to
my Crescenta Makris off is always
looking at like what's what's Apple do
it like what are they doing we gotta hop
on that but like Apple is saying what
does humanity need what is what what do
we do what are we doing like what
they're focusing on themselves not the
competition you know and that's that
really like max was talking about I said
before folks on that 20% that's positive
not the 80% that's negative if that's
the case right right
I think that it's not ain't about alike
it's not about blocking out the haters
it's literally about just like no you
don't need to think about it you just
focus on on improving your own life and
focus on your own lane and creating what
you think you need to create and that's
all you need to do and that is the war
path that I have been on so a wolf of
wallstreet
[Music]
all right all right Ryan Reid you are a
wonderful man you've been a wonderful
guest we've got plenty of more crossing
of paths in life forever hopefully yeah
I [__] agree is there anything that
you want to send off the the listeners
of the junkyard left podcast off with
today thank you for hearing to the
listeners for hearing out all of that
that is like you know I don't again I
know I said this a few times but like I
really don't like put enough personal
stuff onto social media for them to
really know me mmm you don't I mean they
know what I'm doing they know what I'm
up to because of I'll post the moves
what's next show that you know something
they know what I'm doing play the game
you know they don't know me and this was
really this is probably the most me
thing I've done that is gonna be public
in a long time so just like I hope the
listeners stuck it out this far
I hope they got to know me has me a
little bit and you know I hope they're
able to accept me with an open minds and
then therefore I hope it inspires them
to be able to feel like they can grow as
well and that they could become a better
version of who they were and then you
know just work on that undefeated
mindset like work on the fact that like
the only [__] that's gonna bring you
down is the [__] that you let bring you
down yeah and all that just sounds so
dumb like sounds good on paper but look
you know look at look at the adversity
that I've you know had to handle thus
far right and maintaining my positivity
through that and like always feeling
like you know all right if I just if I
just take another step if I just if I
just push
little harder like you know even from
the dark times to the sick times - this
and that it's like if I just if I keep
pushing keep growing and have that faith
that greatness will come from that
then it will it will it'll take a long
time and you'll be exhausted but you if
you chase greatness long enough you will
wrassle that [__] in and it'll all be
worth it yes I believe it so much Ryan
Reid founder of half-life and tell them
where to find you yes so by this point
in time because it'll be March you could
find everything on half-life ent com
that is HAF there's no L in F because
it's earth there's no Helen F there's no
L in half because it is an acronym so
it's HAF life ENT calm or you can find
me online on instagram @ i am ryan reed
i am ryan reed facebook ryan reed
youtube ryan reed pretty much does all
things ryan reed and then a Spotify
Apple music google play all that good
stuff I'm the first one that pops up
when you put in Ryan Reid so wherever
you need to find me if you would a
neither Ryan Reid or I am Ryan Reid I
will pop up but also if you haven't seen
that this is for music video the song
that I just performed here in spoken
word version if you haven't stripped
right exactly stripped down and raw
listen to this is for on either your
streaming service or watch the video
that's online or on my Facebook so with
that being said on YouTube or Facebook
so with that being said thank you so
much I am Ryan Reed with half-life
entertainment here on the junker love
podcast with the amazing Jake rinds I
love you brother I love you man so glad
to have you man thanks so much for this
man absolutely all right have a good
last rest your day listeners please
drink some [__] water come on
you